神鬼交锋
改编自真实故事
欢迎收看《真的假不了》
JOE GARAGlOLA: Thank you very much and welcome to To Tell the Truth.
第一位来宾曾经是职业骗徒
Our first guest, he's made a career out of being the most outrageous impostor
他的行径大胆令人咋舌 你们很快就会知道
that we've ever come across on this show and you're going to see what l mean.
一号，请问尊姓大名？
ANNOUNCER: Number One what is your name, please?
我叫法兰克威康艾巴奈尔
My name is Frank William Abagnale.
二号呢？ 我叫法兰克威康艾巴奈尔
Number Two? My name is Frank William Abagnale.
三号？ 我叫法兰克威康艾巴奈尔
Number Three? My name is Frank William Abagnale.
从1964年到1967年…
GARAGlOLA: ''From 1964 to 1967 ''l successfully impersonated
我成功假扮泛美航空机师
''an airline pilot for Pan Am Airways
免费搭乘两百万哩程的飞机
''and l flew over two million miles for free.
在那段时间内…
''During that time,
我也是一位小儿科主任医师…
l was also the chief resident pediatrician at a Georgia hospital
以及路易西安那州助理检察官
''and an assistant attorney general ''for the State of Louisiana.
我被捕时…
''By the time l was caught,
被认为是美国史上 最年轻最胆大妄为的骗子
l was considered the youngest and most daring con man in U.S. history.
我曾兑现近四百万元伪造支票
''l had cashed almost $4 million in fraudulent checks
遍及全美50州及26个国家
''in 26 foreign countries and all 50 states.
全是我未满19岁前做的事
''And l did it all before my 19th birthday.
我叫法兰克威康艾巴奈尔
My name is Frank William Abagnale.'' # You don't know how to tell the truth... #
这是他生平第一次必须说实话
# You don't know how to tell the truth... # So, for the first time he's going to have to tell the truth
我们先让凯蒂发问
and we're going to start our questioning with Kitty.
谢谢，一号，既然你这么有才华 很显然也非常聪明
Thank you. Number One, why, with all your talent-- and you're obviously a very bright fellow--
为什么不从事正当职业？
why didn't you go in for a legitimate profession?
我是纯粹以投资报酬率考量
lt was really a question of dollars and cents.
我年轻时很缺钱 这是最容易赚钱的方法
When l was a young man, l needed the money and l thought this list of careers was the easiest way to get it.
原来如此，二号 这真是太有意思了
l see. Number Two, l find this all very fascinating.
最后到底是谁逮到你？
Who was it that finally caught you?
他叫卡尔韩瑞提
His name was Carl Hanratty.
韩
Han-an-an-ratty.
瑞提
Ratty.
韩瑞提，卡尔韩瑞提
Hanratty. Han-ratty. Carl Hanratty.
我是…
-Yes. -l...
卡尔韩瑞提
am... Carl Hanratty.
我是美国联邦调查局探员
l represent the FBl from the United States of America.
我获准见美国囚犯艾巴奈尔
Yeah. l have orders to see the American prisoner, Abagnale.
法国马赛，耶诞夜，1969年
Marseille, France Christmas Eve 1969
你坐这儿
You sit here.
不准打开这道门
You do not open the door.
也不准把任何东西…
You do not pass him...
放进这个洞
anything through the hole.
天啊
Aw... Jesus.
我也有一点感冒
You know, l've got a little bit of a cold myself.
法兰克，我是来宣读…
-Frank... l'm here to read the articles of extradition
欧洲人权法庭的引渡条款
according to the European Court for Human Rights.
“第一条…
''Article One:
“引渡程序必须根据 人犯所受的刑罚轻重评估…”
Extradition shall be granted in respect of offenses punishable under the laws...''
救我
Help me. ''...for the maximum period of at least one year
of a severe penalty.''
救救我
Help me.
法兰克，少来了
Frank... stop it.
救救我
Help me.
别以为你能骗过我
You don't think actually you can fool me, do you?
还有16页，“第二条…
16 pages to go. Stay with me. Article Two:
“如果引渡人犯有多项罪名
''lf the request for extradition ''includes several separate offenses
每一项罪名皆可判刑…
each of which is punishable under the laws...'' ''of the requesting party...''
法兰克？
Frank?
可恶！
Goddamn it!
快找医生！我要医生！
-Get me a doctor in here! -l need a doctor!
- 是  - 医生，快
-Yes. Doctor! Now!
放心，我们马上找医生
HANRATTY: Don't sweat it, Frank. We're going to get you right to a doctor.
听我说，你明天一早就能回家
Frank, if you can hear me, don't worry. l'm going to take you home in the morning.
一早就回家
Home in the morning, Frank.
你在干嘛？ 冲掉虱子
What are you doing? Washing off the lice.
他得看医生，然后飞回美国
This man has to be on a plane for America. He has to see a doctor.
医生明天才来
The doctor comes in tomorrow.
我追捕他太久不能让你搞砸
l have worked too long, too hard for you to take this away from me.
他死了我唯你是问
lf he dies, l'm holding you responsible.
先生
Monsieur!
法兰克
Frank.
好吧，卡尔…
Okay, Carl...
咱们回家吧
let's go home.
新洛夏市扶轮社 于1919年成立
MAN: The New Rochelle Rotary Club has a history that goes back to 1919.
这么多年来…
ln all those years
只有少数的精英份子…
we've only seen a handful of deserving gentlemen
有幸成为终身社员
inducted as lifetime members.
总共只有57人获此殊荣…
lt's an honor that, uh
将他们的名字刻在墙上
that has seen 57 names enshrined on the wall of honor
今晚将出现第58名
and tonight, we make it 58.
请站起来欢迎我的好友
So please stand as l present my very good friend
他让我们有写不完的铅笔…
a man who keeps our pencils sharp...
和用不完的墨水
and our pens in ink--
法兰克威康艾巴奈尔
Frank William Abagnale.
六年前
Six years earlier
纽约州新洛夏市，1963年
New Rochelle, New York 1963
我很荣幸…
l stand here humbled
能和劳勃韦纳州长…
by the presence of Mayor Robert Wagner...
以及社长杰克邦恩同台
...and our club president, Jack Barnes.
我更高兴能看到我的爱妻宝拉…
Most of all, l'm honored to see my loving wife Paula...
跟我宝贝儿子小法兰克
...and my son, Frank Jr.--
法兰克，上来
Frank... Aw, stand up. Come on--
他们就坐在前排
...sitting in the front row.
两只小老鼠跌进一桶鲜奶油
Two little mice fell in a bucket of cream.
第一只老鼠很快放弃于是淹死
The first mouse quickly gave up and drowned.
第二只老鼠…
The second mouse...
不肯放弃
wouldn't quit.
他死命地挣扎
He struggled so hard
最后把鲜奶油摇成牛油…
that eventually he churned that cream into butter
然后爬了出来
and crawled out.
各位，我就是第二只老鼠
Gentlemen, as of this moment, l am that second mouse.
你跳得比你爸好
PAULA: You're a better dancer than your father, Frankie.
爸，听到吗？ 了不起
You hear that, Daddy?
小女生不懂得欣赏你
FRANK SR.: Like fun. PAULA: The girls don't know
教他跳我们初识时跳的舞
what they're in for. Show him the dance you were doing when we met.
谁记得呀？
Ah, who can remember?
那些法国村民看到美国大兵
The people in that little French village were so happy to see Americans
高兴得办一场表演晚会
they decided to put on a show for us.
他们把两百个大兵… 我们都知道这故事
So they crammed 200 soldiers... Yeah, we know the story, Daddy.
安排在小小的礼堂…
...into that tiny social hall
第一个上台的就是你妈
and the first person to walk onstage
她开始跳舞
is your mother, and she starts to dance.
我们好久…
You know, it had been months since we'd even seen a woman
没看到女人 这个金发天使
and here's this blonde angel.
金发尤物
Blonde bombshell.
让每个男人停止呼吸
And the men are literally holding their breath.
为了你停止呼吸
Holding their breath for you. You hear that?
我转过头跟同胞说…
And l turned to my buddies and l said...
“我不带她走就不离开法国”
''l will not leave France without her.''
我没食言
And l didn't.
你没有
You didn't.
我没有
l didn't.
该死，地毯弄脏了
Oh, shit! Oh, shit, the rug!
噢，妈… 我是怎么搞的？
Aw, Mom... l can't believe l did that.
没关系
No, no, it's nothing. lt's nothing.
法兰克，去拿纸巾 来啦
Oh, Frankie, Frankie, get a towel. -Yeah, yeah. -Paula...
快点
Come on.
# My sweet embraceable you... #
陪我跳舞，宝拉
Dance with me, Paula.
我一陪你跳舞就有麻烦
Whenever l dance for you l get in trouble.
法兰克，醒醒，走吧
Frank! Wake up. Come on, let's go!
起来，快起来
Get up. Come on, come on.
法兰克，起床 爸爸
Frank, wake up. Dad...
你今天不用上学
You don't have to go to school today. lt's okay.
为什么？下雪了吗？ 你有黑西装吗？
Why? ls it snowing? Do you have a black suit?
我又睡过头了
l overslept again, huh?
今天有很重要的事，吃吧
We have a very important meeting in the city.
快点
Eat that. Come on, come on, eat.
请开门，这很重要
Ma'am, open up. Just open up, please! -Ma'am? -lt's important.
干嘛？
What? Oh, gosh!
我们半小时后才营业 快开门，这很重要
We don't open for half an hour! Open the door, please. Just open the door.
抱歉，半小时后才营业
lt's important. l-l'm sorry, we don't open for half an hour.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name, ma'am?
黛西 好美的名字
Darcy. Darcy. That's a pretty name.
我有急事，我小孩需要黑西装 我儿子法兰克
l'm in a bit of a fix. l need a suit for my kid. This is my son Frank.
他需要黑西装
Oh, hi. He needs a black suit.
我家里有人去世 我爸85岁，他是战争英雄
Black suit... There was a death in the family. My father, 85 years old, war hero. Yeah?
下午有一场军事葬礼
There's a funeral this afternoon, military funeral
战机升空，21声枪响致哀
planes flying overhead, 21-gun salute. Geez.
他得借一套黑西装
Frank needs to borrow a suit for a couple of hours.
我们不借西装，也还没营业
l'm sorry, we don't loan suits, and we're not open.
黛西，请你回来
Darcy... Darcy, please. -Come back.
黛西，这是你的吗？
Darcy... is this yours?
我在停车场捡到的
l just found it in the parking lot. Uh-huh.
一定是你掉的
lt must've slipped right off your neck.
别撞上人行道
Don't hit the curb.
下车，绕过来替我开车门
Now get out, walk around the back and hold the door open for me.
- 然后呢？  - 别一直笑
What's next? Okay, stop grinning.
等我进去你就回车上等
When l get inside, you go back to the front seat and wait.
连警察来开罚单都不要开走
Even if a cop comes and writes you a ticket you don't move the car, understood?
这是怎么回事？
Dad, wha-what's all this for?
洋塞队为什么老是赢球？
You know why the Yankees always win, Frank?
他们有全垒打王米塞曼托？
'Cause they have Mickey Mantle?
不对 因为对手顾着看他们的帅制服
No, it's 'cause the other teams can't stop staring at those damn pinstripes.
你看，大通银行经理…
Watch this. The manager of Chase Manhattan Bank
要替你老爸开门
is about to open the door for your father.
艾先生…
Mr. Abagnale, um
我们通常不贷款给逃漏税的人
we don't usually loan money to people who have unresolved business with the lRS.
那只是误解，我找错会计了
That's a misunderstanding. l hired the wrong guy to do my books.
谁都会犯这种错
A mistake, l... anybody could make it.
请你帮助我渡过难关
l just need you guys to help me weather the storm.
你因为逃漏税被国税局调查
Sir, you're being investigated by the government for tax fraud.
我的店是新洛夏市老店 顾客来自纽约各地
My store is a landmark in New Rochelle. l have customers all over New York.
只可惜你不是本银行的顾客
Well, you're not a customer at Chase Manhattan.
请你回去找你的银行帮忙
We don't know you. l'm sure your bank in New Rochelle they know you, they could help you out.
我的银行倒闭了
My bank went out of business.
被你们这种大银行逼的
Banks like this one put them out of business.
我承认我犯了错
Now, l know l made a mistake, l admit that but these people want blood.
但是国税局要查封我的店 甚至威胁把我关进大牢
They want my store. They've threatened to put me in jail.
这里是美国，我不是坏人
This is America, right? l'm not a criminal.
我得过英勇奖章 我也是扶轮社终身社员
l'm a Medal of Honor winner a lifetime member of the New Rochelle Rotary Club.
请你帮我打赢这场仗
All l'm asking is for you to help me beat these guys.
我们不在乎输赢，只怕有风险
lt's not a question of winning and losing. lt's a question of risk.
你们是世界最大的银行…
You're the largest bank in the world. Where's the fu...
哪来的风险？
Whe... Where's the risk?
你要让他们把车拿走？
Dad, how could you just let him take our car like that?
是我们占了他便宜 他多付了五百元
He didn't take anything. We took him. He overpaid by $500.
来吧，我们去还西装
Come on, Frank. Let's return the suit.
这地方很棒
This place is good.
有点小，不过比较好打理
lt's small but, you know it's going to be a lot less work.
你不用那么辛苦
A lot less work for you.
爸
FRANK: Hey, Dad. Hi.
你妈呢？
Where's your mother?
不知道
l don't know.
她说要去找工作
She said something about going to look for a job.
她要向蜈蚣推销鞋子吗？
What's she gonna be a shoe salesman at a centipede farm?
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
你想吃煎饼吗？
You want some pancakes?
今天是我儿子的十六岁生日
For dinner? On my son's 16th birthday?
我们才不吃煎饼
We're not gonna eat pancakes.
看什么？你以为我忘了？
Come on, why are you looking at me like that? You thought l forgot?
我没这么想 我用你的名字开了…
-l didn't think you forgot. -l opened a checking account
支票帐户
in your name.
我存了25元，随便你怎么用
l put $25 in the account so you can buy whatever you want.
别告诉你妈 不会啦
Don't tell your mother. l won't.
谢了
Thanks, Dad. Yep.
银行不是不贷款给你吗？
Didn't that bank turn you down for a loan, though?
他们全都不肯
Yes, they all turned me down.
那干嘛开个银行户头？
Then why you opening a banking account with them?
有一天你得向他们贷款
Well, because one day, you'll want something
买房子、买车子…
from these people-- a house, a car.
银行有的是钱
They have all the money.
这儿有五十张支票
There's 50 checks there, Frank
这代表从今天起…
which means, from this day on...
你就是他们的会员
you're in their little club.
我是他们的会员
l'm in their little club.
你什么都不用愁了
You got that, you got it all.
上面有我名字耶
lt's even got my name there, huh?
- 一步登天  - 一步登天
To the moon. -To the moon!
一步登天
-To the moon.
你看？这就是公立中学
See that? lt's just a school.
跟私立中学没两样
No different than Westbourne.
妈，你说要戒烟
Ma... you said you were going to quit.
你在这儿不必穿制服
Frankie, you don't have to wear the uniform here.
把外套脱掉吧
Why don't you take off your jacket?
我穿习惯了
l'm used to it.
对不起 什么事？
Excuse me. Oh, yes?
请问17号教室在哪儿？ 在…
Do you know where room 1 7 French is? GlRL: Yeah, it's...
你是推销员吗？
You selling encyclopedias?
他看起来像是代课老师
Yeah, he looks like a substitute teacher.
同学们，安静！
Quiet down, people!
我是艾巴奈尔老师！
My name is Mr. Abagnale!
艾巴奈尔，不是艾巴诺利…
That's Abagnale, not Abagnahlee
或艾巴奈利，是艾巴奈尔
not Abagnaylee, but Abagnale!
请告诉我你们上到哪一课
Now, somebody please tell me where you left off in your textbooks.
没人肯说我就记每位同学小过
Excuse me, people, if l need to ask again l'm going to write up the entire class.
乖乖坐好！
Take your seats!
第七课
Chapter seven.
请你们翻到第八课…
Will you please open your textbooks to, uh, chapter eight
开始上课
and we'll get started?
你叫什么？ 布莱德
Excuse me, what's your name?
请你到课堂前面来
Brad. Brad, why don't you get up here in front of the class here
大声读出第五段对话
and read conversation number five?
''Les Francais sonts
''uh, generalement
-''dans leur pais que...
presque tout le monde a cette impression...''
他们请我来代课
They sent for me.
他们说萝贝塔找人代课
They said they needed a sub for Roberta.
我大老远从狄逊跑来
l came all the way from-from Dixon.
她每次都找我代课
Well, uh, l always sub for Roberta.
你怎么不念了？
Excuse me, why aren't you reading?
我不会再来杰佛逊高中了！
l'll never come back to-to Bellarmine Jefferson again!
叫他们别再找我
-You tell them not to call me!
我这年纪还要大老远赶来
What do they think, it's easy for a woman my age
花了那么多车钱 太可恶了
and all the money that it costs to travel? l tell you, they don't give a damn.
两位…
Mr. and Mrs. Abagnale
令郎并没有跷课
this is not a question of your son's attendance.
这一个礼拜来…
l regret to inform you that, for the past week
他都在教葛老师的法文课
Frank has been teaching Mrs. Glasser's French class.
什么？
He what?
你们的儿子假扮成代课老师
Your son has been pretending to be a substitute teacher
替学生上课，发作业…
lecturing the students, uh, giving out homework.
葛老师请病假
Mrs. Glasser has been ill and there was
真的代课老师出了点状况
some confusion with the real sub.
他昨天举行家长会
Your son held a teacher-parent conference yesterday
还想到法国面包工厂…
and was planning a class field trip
课外教学
to a French bread factory in Trenton.
这是个大问题
Do you see the problem we have?
我五、六节课要请假 我得去看医生
-Mrs. Davenport? -Yeah. Uh, l have a note to miss fifth and sixth period today. Doctor's appointment.
等一下，我马上来
-One moment. l'll be right with you.
你应该折起来 什么？
MRS. DAVENPORT: Yes? You should fold it. What?
纸条是假的，你要折起来
That note. lt's a fake, right? You should fold it.
这是我妈写的，我跟医生有约
lt's... lt's a note from my mom. l have a doctor's appointment.
纸条没有折痕
Yeah, but there's no crease in the paper.
如果你妈给你一张纸条…
When your mom hands you a note to miss school
你一定会折起来放进口袋
the first thing you do is, you fold it and you put it in your pocket.
折痕呢？
l mean, if it's real, where's the crease?
法兰克
Frankie.
妈，我回来了
Ma, l'm home.
记得我跟你提过的琼安
Oh, you remember that girl Joanna l was telling you about?
我今天约了她
l asked her out today.
我们要参加二年级舞会
Think we're going to go to the Junior Prom.
这是我的驾照吗？
Ma, is this my driver's license?
就这样，两间卧室
That's all there is, two bedrooms.
法兰克
Oh, Frankie.
这是爸的朋友
You remember Dad's friend?
扶轮社的杰克邦恩
Jack Barnes? From the club.
他来找你爸
He came by looking for your father.
我带他参观一下
l was giving him a tour of the apartment.
这儿真的很大
lt's very, uh, uh, spacious, Paula.
爸在店里
Dad's at the store.
法兰克…
So, Frank... you're getting to look
你越来越像你老爸了
more like your old man every day.
谢谢你的三明治
Thanks for the sandwich, Paula.
回头见 等等
l'll see you later, eh? Wait.
这是你的吗？
ls this yours? Oh.
谢了，这是社长别针
Well, thanks, Frank. Uh, that's the President's pin.
搞丢了麻烦就大了
l'd be in deep trouble if l lost that.
再见了
l'll see you all later, eh?
饿了吗？我做三明治给你吃
Are you hungry, Frankie? l'll make you a sandwich.
杰克想跟你爸谈公事
Jack wanted to talk business with your father.
他说我们应该请律师告政府
He thinks we should get a lawyer and sue the government.
政府那么对我们不合法
That is not legal, what they're doing to us.
你怎么不说话？
Why aren't you saying anything?
你不会跟他说吧？
You're not going to tell him... are you?
不会
No.
没错，没什么好说的
That's right. There's nothing to tell.
我要去找网球社的老朋友
l'm going out for a few hours to visit some old friends from the tennis club and...
我回来就一起吃晚饭
when l get home, we'll all have dinner together.
好吗？
Right?
你什么都不会说…
But you won't say anything
对吧？
because it's... it's just silly, isn't it?
我们怎么能告政府呢？
How could we sue anybody?
你要零用钱吗？
Oh... do you need some money, Frankie?
拿去买唱片
A few dollars to buy some record albums?
来，五块钱
Here, take five dollars.
十块钱
Or-Or ten.
你说你要戒烟的
You promised you were going to quit.
我回来了
Ma, l'm home!
离我远一点
Hey, hey! You... You stay away from me, hear me?
不管你是谁，别再回来…
You stay away from me-- l don't know who you are but if you ever come back here again--
冷静点，我是狄克卡斯纳
Frankie! Frank, Frank, calm down, will you? l'm Dick Kesner.
把东西放下，跟我来
Now, l want you to leave your things here and follow me into the next room, okay?
他们都在等你
They're all waiting for you.
别害怕，我在这儿
PAULA: You don't have to be scared.
我会一直陪着你
l'm right here, Frank. l'll always be here.
不过在美国一切都得合法
But there are laws. Everything in this country has to be legal.
我们必须做一些决定 所以卡先生才会来
So what we need to do is make some decisions. That's what Mr. Kesner is here for.
很多时候法院必须做决定
Many times these decisions are left up to the courts
为了争取抚养权打官司很花钱
but that can be very expensive, Frank people fighting over their children.
没有人在争吵
Nobody is fighting.
看着我，我们没争吵 （法语）爸，这是怎么回事？
Look at me, Frank. Nobody is fighting.
Dad, what's going on?
你记得你外婆吗？ 她早上才到的
Do you remember your grandma, Eve? She arrived this morning.
你明白我们说的话吗？
Do you understand what we're saying to you, Frank?
我跟你爸要离婚
Your father and l are getting a divorce.
什么也没变，我们还是能见面
Nothing's gonna change. We're still gonna see each other.
住口，别插嘴 你不必全都看完
Stop it, please, Frank. Don't interrupt. Frank, you don't have to read all of this.
多半都是大人的事情
Most of it's for your parents-- boring adult business--
只有这一段最重要
but this paragraph right here, this is important
这里说你在爸妈离婚后…
because it states who you're gonna live with...
你要跟谁一起住
after the divorce...
你的抚养权归谁
whose custody you will be in.
这儿有一个空格
And there's a blank space right here.
我要你到厨房…
And l want you to go into the kitchen sit at the table
写下一个名字
and put a name down.
慢慢来，不过等你回来…
You can take as long as you want but when you come back into this room...
我要看到一个名字
l want to see a name on that line.
你只要写下一个名字就行了
Frank, just write down a name and this will all be over.
不会有事的
lt's gonna be okay.
什么名字？
FRANK: Dad, what name?
你爸或你妈的名字，很简单
Your mother or your father. Just put the name there. lt's as simple as that.
别害怕，这不是考试
And don't look so scared. lt's not a test.
没有错误答案
There's no wrong answer.
一张到纽约的车票
One ticket to Grand Central, please.
三块半
That'll be $3.50, sir.
你收支票吗？
ls it okay if l write you a check?
我几时能打给我爸？
Carl, when do l get to call my father?
到了纽约再说
You can call him when we get to New York. Paris, France 1969
七小时后到机场
We leave for the airport in seven hours.
法国巴黎，1969年
乖乖坐好
Until then, just sit there.
别出声
Be quiet.
另外一边的房间面对公园
You know, Carl, on the other side of the hotel they got suites that face the park.
FBI只能住这儿
lt's the best room the FBl can afford.
无所谓，我住过更差的
lt's okay, l've stayed in worse. Mr. Mudrick...
求求你，听我说
Mr. Mudrick, please. You have to listen.
我不想听，你开了两张芭乐票
l don't want to hear your story. This is two checks that bounced.
我的麻烦够大了
You know how much trouble l'm in?
银行搞错了，我再写张给你！
No, but listen, l'm telling you, the bank, they made the mistake. l'll write you another check right now!
我看起来像猪头吗？
What, do l look like l was born yesterday?
现在是午夜，我该去哪儿？
Look, it's midnight, Mr. Mudrick. Where am l gonna go?
你是个孩子，回家吧
You're a goddamn kid. Go home.
法兰克泰勒
请你体谅一下 老板派我到布鲁克林和皇后区
l mean, l hope you understand. My boss sent me to Brooklyn, then Queens.
现在又要我去长岛…
Now he wants me in Long lsland
招待客户
to take a few clients out for a night on the town.
抱歉，这不是本行的支票
l'm sorry, but we're not allowed to cash checks from other banks.
我们怎么知道能不能兑现？ 你叫什么来着？
How would we know if they were any good? What did you say your name was?
艾希莉
Ashley.
我在街上捡到一样东西
Ashley... you know what l found on the sidewalk out there?
这一定是你掉的
Must've slipped right off your neck.
我能效劳吗，年轻人？
ls there something l can help you with, son?
我外婆下星期生日 我想送她一份大礼
Well, you see, it's my grandmother's birthday next week and l want to get her something extra-special.
我下礼拜期中考，课本却被偷
Please, l mean it's my midterm next week and my books were stolen.
只有五块钱，谁也不知道
Please, it's just five dollars. No one would have to know.
很抱歉，我们不能兑现…
l'm sorry, but we are not allowed
来路不明的支票
to take checks from people we don't know.
欢迎到纽约
很高兴再见到你
Pleasure to have you back, Captain Carlson.
怎么样？这些妞儿有够辣
What do you think, Angelo? The tomatoes are ripe this afternoon.
怎么回事？
Well, what have we here?
你能帮我签名吗？ 当然能
-Can l have your autograph? -You betcha.
我也要你签名 你想当机师吗？
-Can l have your autograph, too? -You gonna be a pilot? -Mm-hmm! -All right, then.
拿去，好好用功
There you go. Work hard in school.
亲爱的爸…
FRANK: Dear Dad;
我决定当机师
l have decided to become an airline pilot.
我到每家航空公司应征 安排了好多面试机会
l have applied to all the big airlines and l have several promising interviews lined up.
妈好不好？你有打给她吗？
How's Mom? Have you called her lately?
你的儿子法兰克敬上
Love, your son, Frank.
我是蒙洛中学的法兰克 我跟摩根先生有约
l'm Frank Black from Murrow High School and l have an appointment with Mr. Morgan.
就是你在校刊上写文章
You're the young man who's writing the article for the school paper.
是的，我想了解机师的一切
Yes, ma'am, that's me. l want to know everything there is to know about being a pilot.
泛美航空都飞去哪儿？ 机师一年赚多少钱？
What airports does Pan Am fly to? What does a pilot make in a year?
谁告诉他们该飞到哪儿？
And who tells them where they're gonna fly to?
慢一点，一次一个问题 好的
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Slow down. Just take 'em one at a time.
当一个机师问“你用什么装备？" 那是什么意思？
All right. What does it mean when one pilot says to another pilot: ''What kind of equipment are you on?''
他想知道你开的机型 DC 8、707等等…
They just want to know what kind of aircraft you're flying: ls it a DC-8, 707, Constellation?
机师配戴的识别名牌呢？
And what about those l.D. badges that l've seen pilots wear?
机师必须随身携带两样东西
Well, every pilot has to have two things with him
航空公司员工识别证 就跟这个一样
at all times: One is his airline personnel badge-- looks just like this one here, from Pan Am--
另一个是飞行员执照
the other one is their FAA license...
看起来就像这个
and that looks just like this.
我能影印一份登在校刊上吗？
Oh. Sir, do you think l can make a copy of this to put into my article?
拿去吧，这过期三年了
Oh, Frank, you can have that one. lt's three years expired.
谢了 你有多余的识别证能借我吗？
Aw, thanks! And what about your l.D. badge? You have an extra one l could borrow?
那就恐怕没办法了 这是向拍立得公司订做的
Oh, no, l can't help you there. Those are special-ordered from Polaroid.
成为泛美航空机师…
The only way to get one of those
才拿得到
is to become a real live pilot for Pan American Airways.
泛美航空，我能效劳吗？
Pan Am, may l help you?
我打来问制服的事
Yeah, hello. l'm calling about a uniform.
请稍候 谢谢
WOMAN: Hold for Purchasing.
采购组
FRANK: Thank you. WOMAN 2: Purchasing.
我是旧金山来的副机长
Hi. l'm a copilot based out of San Francisco.
我昨晚才到纽约 三小时后就要飞到巴黎
l flew a flight into New York last night but the problem is l'm headed out to, uh, Paris in three hours.
我能帮什么忙？
WOMAN 2: How can we help you?
我请旅馆帮我把制服送洗
FRANK: l sent my uniform to be cleaned through the hotel
结果被他们搞丢了
and l... l guess they must have lost it.
这种事经常发生
WOMAN 2: They lost a uniform. Happens all the time.
请你到合身制服公司 他们专门替我们做制服
Go down to the Well-Built Uniform Company at Ninth and Broadway. They're our uniform supplier.
我跟罗先生说你会去
l'll tell Mr. Rosen you're coming.
你当机长未免太年轻了
ROSEN: You look too young to be a pilot.
我是副机长
l'm a copilot.
你干嘛这么紧张？
Why so nervous?
我才第一个礼拜就把制服弄丢
How would you feel if you, uh lost your uniform first week on the job?
放心，泛美有很多制服
Relax. Pan Am's got lots of uniforms.
164元
lt's gonna be $164.
好，我写支票给你
Great. l'll, uh, l'll write you a check.
抱歉，不收支票或现金
Sorry, no checks, no cash.
请填下你的员工识别号码
You'll have to fill in your employee l.D. number
泛美会直接从你的薪水和除
and then l'll bill Pan Am. They'll take it out of your next paycheck.
这样更棒
Even better.
亲爱的爸…
FRANK: Dear Dad;
你总是说老实人没什么好害怕
You always told me that an honest man has nothing to fear.
所以我试着显得不害怕
So l'm trying my best not to be afraid.
我不该逃家，但你不用担心
l'm sorry l ran away, but you don't have to worry.
我会帮你把钱赚回来 我一定帮你把钱都赚回来
l'm gonna get it all back now, Daddy. l promise. l'm going to get it all back.
你是真的机师吗？
GlRL: Are you a real live pilot?
是啊，小妹妹，你叫什么？
l sure am, little lady. What's your name?
瑟琳 很高兴见到你
Celine. Celine, it's a pleasure to meet you.
我也很高兴见到你
lt's a pleasure to meet you, too.
五十、七十
That's fifty, seventy
八十、九十… 一百元
eighty, ninety, one hundred dollars.
到巴黎玩得愉快
You have yourself a great time in Paris.
我一定会
l always do.
对不起
Excuse me.
我是分行经理莫约翰 谢谢你光顾本银行
l'm John Modiger. l manage this branch. l want to thank you for coming in and using our institution.
幸会了，我会再来的 很好
Well, it's a pleasure to meet you, John. l'll be back again. Good.
你来住过吗？
Have you stayed with us before?
没有，我通常都飞西岸
Uh, no, l've been primarily based on the West Coast.
我能给你支票吗？
ls it all right if l write you a check for the room?
没问题 太好了
No problem, sir. Great.
我能用个人支票吗？
l was also wondering if l could write you a personal check?
个人支票能兑现一百元
For airline personnel, we cash personal checks up to $100.
薪资支票则可兑现三百元
Payroll checks we cash up to $300.
你说薪资支票是三百？
Did you say $300 for a payroll check?
亲爱的爸…
FRANK: Dear Dad;
我决定当泛美航空机师
l've decided to become a pilot for Pan American Airways...
泛美是最值得信赖的航空公司
the most trusted name in the skies.
我参加他们的训练课程 我只要努力…
They've accepted me into their training program and told me that if l work hard
很快就能成功
l should earn my wings real soon.
请你跟琼安联络
Please get in touch with Joanna Carlton from the tenth grade.
跟她说我不能带她参加舞会
Tell her l'm sorry that l could not take her to the Junior Prom.
你的儿子法兰克敬上
Love, your son, Frank.
你好吗？ 很好，谢谢
Hello, how are you? Fine, thank you.
我要兑现一张薪资支票
l have a payroll check here l'd like to cash.
没问题
Certainly. Thank you.
对不起
Uh, excuse me.
你一定常听到这种赞美
l'm sure you hear this all the time
我没见过这么美的眼睛
but you have the most beautiful eyes l have ever seen.
我是常常听到
Yeah, l do get that all the time.
你要什么面额？
How would you like it?
很抱歉，银行一小时后才开门
Oh, l'm sorry, sir. We won't have any cash until the banks open in an hour
不过机场一定会替你兑现
but, uh, l'm sure they can cash your check at the airport.
机场？
The airport?
谁会在机场兑现支票？
Who cashes checks at the airport?
航空公司呀 他们一向都照顾自己人
Well, the airlines, sir. They've always taken care of their own.
你好 你要搭“顺风机”吗？
Hello. Hi. Are you deadheading?
什么？
What?
你要搭顺风机到迈阿密？
Are you my deadhead to Miami? Mi...?
对，对
Yes, yes.
我要搭顺风机
Yeah, l'm the deadhead. Here you go.
你迟到了，但是有空位
You're a little late, but the jump seat is open.
我好久没飞了 都忘了空位是哪个座位
it's been awhile since l've done this. Which one's the jump seat again?
祝你飞行愉快
Have a nice flight.
你要搭顺风机吗？
Are you my deadhead?
奥立佛机长 副机长约翰拉肯
STEWARDESS: Frank, Captain Oliver. -John Larkin, the copilot. -Hello.
飞航技师佛瑞德杜利
Fred Tulley, flight engineer.
泛美的法兰克泰勒，多谢了
Frank Taylor, Pan Am. Thanks for giving me a lift, boys.
坐吧，就要起飞了
Go ahead and take a seat, Frank. We're about to push.
你用什么装备？DC8吗？
What kind of equipment you on, DC-8?
707.
你马上要热夜折回吗？
You turning around on the redeye?
这几个月我都要到处飞来飞去
Uh, l'm jumping puddles for the next few months
有人请病假就代班多赚点钱
trying to earn my keep running leapfrogs for the weak and weary.
这很正常，我们都干过
No shame in that. We all did it.
- 请坐  - 谢了
Have a seat. Thank you.
起飞后你要喝点什么？
Would you like a drink after takeoff?
牛奶？
M-Milk?
- 八十节  - 对
OLlVER: 80 knots. LARKlN: Check.
决定速度、机鼻拉高
V-one. Rotate.
安全速度
V-two. Positive rate.
起落架升起
Gear up.
亲爱的爸：今天我毕业了
FRANK: Dear Dad; Today was graduation.
我现在是副机长 月薪一千四加上福利
l am now a copilot earning $1,400 a month plus benefits
最棒的是我的家人能免费搭机
and the best part is they tell me my family can fly for free.
叫妈收拾行李买泳衣
So tell Mom to pack her bags and buy a new swimsuit
我要带你们去夏威夷过耶诞节
because l'm taking us all to Hawaii for Christmas.
我爱你，爸
l love you, Dad. Aloha, Frank.
你好 你好
Hello, deadhead. Hello.
你还愉快吗？
Enjoying your free ride?
玛西…
Marci...
这是你的吗？
did you drop this?
一定是你掉的 不
Must've slipped right off your neck. No...
不！
No!
好，好！
No... MARCl: Yes, yes, yes, yes!
好！
Yes!
你为什么停下来？
Why are you stopping?
我想跟你说一件事
l want to tell you something, Marci.
这绝对是…
This is by far...
我最棒的“第一次”约会
the best date l have ever been on.
欢迎，我能效劳吗？
Welcome to Miami Mutual Bank. How may l help you?
我是法兰克，泛美航空副机长
My name is Frank Taylor. l'm a copilot for Pan Am.
我要兑现这张支票…
l'd like to cash this check here, and then
然后请你吃顿牛排大餐
l'd like to take you out for a steak dinner.
我把支票放进磁墨字元阅读机
And then we feed the checks into the MlCR machine
支票帐号是用特殊墨水印刷
which uses special ink to encode the account numbers on the bottom of the checks.
支票上的这些号码是什么？
And where are these numbers?
- 在这儿  - 这儿？
They're, um... right here. Right there? See?
这叫银行代码
They're called routing numbers.
这些支票被送到哪儿？
So where do the checks get routed to?
我不知道耶，没人问过我
You know, l don't exactly know. Nobody ever asked me that before.
下一件物件来自泽西中央银行
AUCTlONEER: Our next item up for bid is also from the Jersey Central Bank foreclosure.
磁墨字元键印机 是支票编码用的
This is a MlCR encoder a machine used to encode bank checks.
有人起价吗？
Do l have an opening bid?
这名嫌犯在东岸伪造支票
HANRATTY: Our unknown subject is a paperhanger who started working on the East Coast.
他的诈欺手法很高明 我称之为流动手法
ln the last few weeks, this unsub has developed a new form of check fraud which l'm calling ''the float.''
他在不同的银行开支票帐户…
What he's doing is he's opening checking accounts at various banks
然后窜改支票上面的银行代码
then changing the MlCR ink routing numbers at the bottom of those checks.
下一张幻灯片
Next slide, please.
下一张
遥控器坏了，你要用手动的
Uh, the remote thing is broken. You'll have to do it by hand.
联邦调查局总部，华府
You've gotta... try the... FBl Headquarters Washington, D.C.
旁边应该有方形按纽
Agent Mullen, it should be... it should be the square button just there by the side.
这个转盘坏了
This carousel doesn't work. lt's a bad carousel you got there.
谢谢 我们要用手动的
Thank you, Agent Mullen. Got to move it manually.
这是联邦储备银行的分布图
This is a map of the 12 banks of the U.S. Federal Reserve.
下一张
Slide.
每家银行都会读取银行代码
MlCR scanners at every bank read these numbers at the bottom of a check--
下一张 然后把支票送到开票分行
slide-- and then, ship that check off to its corresponding branch.
我们对银行诈欺案不是很懂
Carl, for those of us who are unfamiliar with bank fraud
你到底在说什么呀？
you mind telling us what the hell you're talking about?
东岸分行的代码从01到06
The East Coast branches are numbered zero-one to zero-six.
中西部则是07、08等等
The central branch is zero-seven, zero-eight
原来这些号码有玄机？
so on, so forth. You mean those numbers on the bottom of a check actually mean something?
我两天前的报告写得很清楚 如果你…
All of this was in the report l filed two days ago. lf you change... a zero-two to a one-two
把02改成12 就代表这张在纽约兑现的支票…
that means that check, which was cashed in New York
不会被送到纽约联邦分行
does not go to the New York Federal Branch
而是会送到旧金山分行
but it is rerouted all the way to the San Francisco Federal Branch.
银行要在两星期后才知道跳票
The bank doesn't even know the check has bounced for two weeks
嫌犯可以待在同一个地方
which means our unsub can stay in one place
不停伪造支票而不会被发现
paper the same city over and over again while his checks circle the country.
你最好去找我老婆
You know, you want to talk to my wife.
我家的支票都是她在管
She's the one balances the checkbook at our house.
下一张
Next slide.
爸
Daddy!
我儿子是机师，好帅的制服
My son, the birdman. Some uniform, Frank.
你觉得怎样？
What do you think?
不错
Nice.
坐吧
Sit down.
你收到明信片吗？
So, Dad... Daddy, have you gotten the postcards?
当然了
Of course.
这支叉子好冰
This fork is ice cold.
爸，这是冰过的沙拉叉
No, no, Dad, th-that's a chilled salad fork.
这是家高级餐馆
lt's a fancy restaurant, you know.
给你
Well, here...
我要送你礼物 那是什么？
l-l got you something. What's that?
打开来
Open it.
你知道这是什么吗？
You know what those are, right?
65年份凯迪拉克敞篷车钥匙
Those are the keys to a 1965 Cadillac DeVille convertible.
全新的哦，红色车身、全白座椅
Brand-new, Dad. Red with white interior
还有冷气，应有尽有
split seats, air conditioning, the works.
你送我一辆凯迪拉克？
Are you giving me a Cadillac?
对，我送你一辆凯迪拉克
Yeah. l'm giving you a Cadillac.
它就停在楼下
Dad, sh-she's parked downstairs.
你吃完饭就开车去接妈
When we're done eating lunch why don't you, you know, drive on over to Mom's house
载她去兜兜风
pick her up, take a little joyride?
你知道我开一辆新车…
Do you know what would happen if the lRS found out
被国税局查到会怎样吗？
l was driving around in a new coupe?
我搭火车来，也要搭火车回去
l took the train here, Frank. l'm taking the train home.
好吧
All right.
我有很多钱
l have plenty of money.
你要什么就说一声
You know, if you ever, ever need anything...
你在替我担心？
You worried? About me?
没有，我不担心
No, l'm not... l'm not worried.
你以为我买不起新车？
You think l can't buy my own car?
两只老鼠跌进一桶鲜奶油
Two mice fell in a bucket of cream, Frank.
我是哪一只？
Which one am l?
你是第二只
You're that second mouse.
我今天经过店里
l went by the store today.
我把店收起来 最重要的是时机
l had to close the store for awhile. lt's all about timing, Frank.
政府总是喜欢落井下石
The goddamn government knows that. They hit you when you're down.
我才不会让他们逼我倒闭 所以我…
l wasn't going to let them take it from me, so l just...
干脆自己先关门大吉
shut the doors myself, called their bluff.
他们迟早会忘了我
Sooner or later, they'll forget about me.
我知道
l understand, l...
你跟妈说了吗？
Have you told Ma?
你妈太固执了
She's so stubborn, your mother.
放心，我不会轻易放弃她
Don't worry. l'm not going to let her go without a fight.
我在努力争取…
l been fighting for us...
爸？
Dad?
从我们见面那天开始
...since the day we... we met.
当时有那么多男人追她…
Daddy, out of all those men
你却带她回家，记得吗？
you were the one that took her home, remember that.
两百个男人…
200 men, sitting in that tiny social hall
挤在那儿看她跳舞
watching her dance.
那座小镇叫什么？ 蒙瑞榭
What was the name of that town? Montrichard, Dad.
我一句法文也不会
l didn't speak a word of French
六星期后却把她娶回家
and six weeks later, she was my wi...
她还是你老婆
She's your wife.
我儿子送我一辆凯迪拉克 我们该举杯庆祝
My son bought me a Cadillac today. l think that calls for a toast.
敬空中最棒的机长
To the best damn pilot in the sky.
不是啦，我只是副机长
lt's not what you think. l'm just a copilot.
大家都在盯着你看
You see these people staring at you?
他们是有钱有势的大人物
These are the most powerful people in New York City
却一直偷看你，猜你要去哪里
and they keep peeking over their shoulders wondering where you're going tonight.
你要去哪里？
Where you going, Frank?
没有人在偷看我
Dad, nobody's staring at me.
新奇的地方？
Some place exotic?
告诉我你要去哪里
Just tell me where you're going.
洛杉…  好莱坞
Los An... Hollywood.
好莱坞？
Hollywood.
过来
Come here
除了你以外，我们都是傻爪
The rest of us... really are suckers.
我穿上红色洋装和高跟鞋
So, l got on this red dress and these high heels, right?
还戴了超大的奶罩
And l got a bra, like, out here, okay?
在公园狂追两个波多黎各佬
And l'm chasing these two Puerto Rican guys through the park.
加州，好莱坞 他们刚干下一票银行抢案
Hollywood California They got a suitcase filled with bank robbery loot.
我大叫："FBI，站住！
Okay, l'm screaming out, ''FBl, freeze!''
可是我摸不到枪
And l'm reaching for my gun, but l can't find it in the bra.
奶罩太大了，我差点射到味味
lt's so damn big l thought l was going to shoot my tits off.
这很好笑，每个人都会笑
You know, that's a funny story. People always laugh at that story.
让我问你，安先生
Let me ask you a question, Mr. Amdursky.
你当卧底这么好玩干嘛请调？
lf you were having so much fun undercover why did you transfer to bank fraud?
我没有请调，我是被贬职
l didn't transfer. l was censured and reassigned.
我犯了错所以被惩罚
lt's like being punished. l was punished. l screwed up in the field.
福先生，你也一样吗？
What about you, Mr. Fox? Were you... punished for screwing up in the field?
我没当过卧底
Oh, no, no, no, l've never worked in the field before.
我之前负责调查新进人员背景
l audited background investigations of Department of Justice clerical applicants.
棒呆了，他们找来两个逊角色
Well, that's just great. l ask for a team and they drag the bottom of the Pacific.
我想问你
You mind if l ask you a question, Agent Hanratty?
你干嘛老是这么严肃？ 你觉得很困扰吗？
How come you're so serious all the time? Does it bother you, Mr. Amdursky?
是有一点困扰
Yeah. Yeah, it does bother me.
你呢，福先生？
Does it bother you, Mr. Fox?
也有一点吧
A little, l guess.
你们想听我说笑话吗？
Well, would you like to hear me tell a joke?
好啊，当然想听
Yeah. Yeah, we'd love to hear a joke from you.
敲敲门
Knock, knock.
谁呀？
Who's there?
去死吧
Go fuck yourselves.
# Tall and tan and young and lovely #
# The girl from lpanema... #
他写的三张支票全都兑现
MAN: He cashed three checks. They all cleared.
我今天要去存这一张
l was going to deposit this one today.
我不想惹麻烦
l don't want any trouble.
不会
No trouble. No trouble at all.
一点都不麻烦
We'll just take this check and be on our way.
我们拿了支票就走，谢谢
Thank you. Good.
那就好，别打扰我的住客
Because l don't want my customers harassed. # ...Each one she passes goes ahh... #
他还在这儿？
What are you saying, he's still here?
201室
201 . # ...Oh, but he watches so sadly... #
谢谢
Thank you.
- 转角  - 谢谢
Corner here. Oh, thanks, son. # ...How can he tell her he loves her... #
楼梯 楼梯
Some steps. Steps.
墨老伯，你好
Hey, Mr. Murphy, how are you?
法兰克？ 对
ls that Frank? Yeah, it's Frank.
你好吗？ 你的膝盖怎样？
Hey, Frank, how are you?
拜托，我能跟你赛跑
How's the knee? Come on, l'll race you right now.
保重 好
Take care. Okay, Frank.
守后门？ 这家伙只会动笔，不会用枪啦…
AMDURSKY: ''Eyeball the back''? Come on, Carl, this guy's a pen and ink man. A goddamn paperhanger.
我们跟你去吧
He doesn't even carry a gun.
提高警觉，待会请你们吃针筒
You just keep your eyes open, do your job and l'll buy you both a Good Humor bar.
别怕，我是FBI
lt's all right, ma'am. FBl.
2 01室
201 ... 201 , 201 .
201 ...
201 ... 201 ... 201 ... 201 ...
FBI !
FBI!
F Bl ! FBl!
从里面出来！
Come out of the bathroom!
从浴室里出来！
Step out of the bathroom!
手放在头上 那是全新IBM打字机
Hands on your head. Oh, that's the new lBM Selectric.
把手放在头上… 要更换字型匣很容易…
Put your hands on your head. You can change the print type in five seconds.
闭嘴！
-Shut up! -Just pop out the ball.
手放在头上！
Put your hands on your head! Put your hands...!
他有两百张支票 一加仑的印度墨水…
You know, he's got over 200 checks here, a gallon -of lndia ink, drafting. -Hands on your head!
连泛美航空的薪资信封都有…
Even has little payroll envelopes
放下来！给我放下来！ 别紧张！
addressed to himself from Pan Am. Put it down! Drop it! Relax.
你晚了一步
You're late, all right?
我是秘勤局的贝瑞艾伦 嫌犯跳窗逃走
My name's Allen, Barry Allen United States Secret Service. Your boy just tried to jump out the window.
我搭档逮到他 我不知道你在说什么
My partner has him in custody downstairs. l don't know what you're talking about.
你以为只有FBI想逮他吗？ 拜托
You think the FBl are the only ones on this guy? l mean, come on.
他窜改政府支票
Come on, he's dabbling in government checks here.
我们追了他好几个月
We've been following a paper trail on this guy for months now.
别拿枪指着我，我会紧张
Hey, you mind taking that gun out of my face? Please. Really. l mean, it makes me nervous.
给我看证件
Let me see some credentials.
好
Yeah, sure.
我的皮夹给你
Take my whole wallet.
过来呀，连我的枪都拿去
You want my gun, too? Come over here. Take my gun.
帮帮忙，看看窗外
Hey, hey, look, just do me a favor. Take a look outside. Look. Look out the window.
我搭档正在押他上车
My partner's walking him to the car as we speak-- Look.
我冲进来那老家伙差点到尿
Old guy almost pissed in his pants when l came through the door.
他直接跳到我的车上
He jumped right through the window onto the hood of my car.
莫夫？
Hey, Murph? -Yeah?
打给洛城警局，叫他们快来
-Call the LAPD again. l don't want people walking through my crime scene.
我不知道秘勤局也参一脚
l didn't expect the Secret Service on this.
别担心，你叫什么？
Don't worry about it. Well, what's your name?
卡尔韩瑞提
Hanratty, Carl Hanratty.
我能看你的证件吗？
Mind if l see some identification? Sure.
这年头得提防小人
You never can be too careful these days.
算你倒霉
Well, tough luck, Carl.
你早来五分钟就能立下大功 是吗？
Five minutes earlier you would've landed yourself a pretty good collar. lt's all right.
我晚来十秒你就挂了
Ten seconds later, and you'd have been shot. Mind if l come downstairs with you?
我跟你下去，我想看看他
l-l got to take a look at this guy.
没问题 等一下，我先把物证搬下去
Sure thing. Just, uh, do me a favor and sit tight for a second while l get this evidence downstairs.
我不想让女佣进来搞乱
You know, l don't want some maid walking through here
洛城警察随时都会到 等一下
and making the bed. LAPD should be here any sec. Wait.
你的皮夹
Your wallet.
先帮我拿着，我信任你
You hang onto it for a minute. l trust you.
秘勤局
Secret Service.
可恶！
Oh, goddamn it!
我真蠢，我犯了蠢错误
lt was stupid. l made a stupid mistake.
算了啦
Forget about it.
外头有几百名嫌犯
There are hundreds of unknown subjects out there.
我逮得到他 这种智慧罪犯不该露脸
l-l can get this guy, Sean. The worst thing a paperhanger can do is show his face.
我看过报告
l read the report.
6尺高，棕发，27到30岁，160磅 这种人到处都是
Six feet tall, brown hair, 27 to 30 years of age 160 pounds. This could be almost anybody.
我听过他声音，看到他的脸 他再也躲不了
l heard his voice, Sean, l saw his face. There's nothing for him to hide behind anymore.
小心点
Just be careful. You got 12 years in.
你有十二年资历
上头很信任你
Nobody bothers you down on the first floor. You practically wrote the book on bank fraud.
你对银行诈欺了若指掌 有一天会升为主任
That's the kind of thing that can make you section chief someday.
别让自己碰到这种情况
Just don't put yourself in this type of position.
什么情况？
What type of position?
这种丢脸的情况
Position of being humiliated.
你想听笑话吗？
Sean, would you like to hear me tell a joke?
好啊
Yeah, sure.
敲敲门
Knock, knock!
我下个问题是…
FRANK: So, my-my next question is, when a pilot retires
机师退休后…
uh, Pan Am sends them a check every single month?
泛美每个月还寄给他们支票？ 对，他们有退休金和福利
Uh, yeah, pension program sends a check and benefits.
每个月多少钱？
How much is that check for?
我没心情谈这些 空中大盗快把我逼疯了
Uh, kid, l'm really not in the mood for this right now. This Skywayman's driving me crazy.
空中大盗是谁？
Who's the Skywayman?
他假扮成泛美机师招摇撞骗
Ah, some nut that's flying around the country posing as a Pan Am pilot.
今天报纸有他的报导
There's a column about him in the paper today.
这与我无关，他又没搭过泛美
l keep telling them this is not my problem. This guy doesn't even fly Pan Am.
别的航空公司都搭过 联合航空、环球航空… 大陆航空、东方航空
Flies everybody else. Flies United, TWA, Continental, Eastern...
空中大盗
The Skywayman.
报纸超爱这跳梁小丑
Newspaper loves this clown.
他被称为空中的詹姆斯庞德
They call him ''the James Bond of the sky.''
你是说…
Did you say...?
庞德，詹姆斯庞德
Bond, James Bond.
告诉我，他为什么这么做？
BOND: Tell me, Joan, why does he do it?
他喜欢当赢家
WOMAN: He likes to win. MAN: Come on, come on.
20分钟后降落
WOMAN: We'll be landing in 20 minutes.
你想吃软还是吃硬？
Do you want to play it easy or the hard way?
这可不是麻醉枪
And this isn't a tranquilizer.
小妞，你挺懂飞机和枪嘛
Well, Pussy, you do know a lot more about planes than guns.
哈罗，小妞
Hello, Pussy.
你确定就是这套西装？
Now, you're sure this is the suit, right?
确定
Positive.
跟电影一模一样
lt's the exact suit he wore in the movie.
好，我要三套
Okay. l'll take three.
没问题，佛莱明先生
Certainly, Mr. Fleming.
你只缺他开的那种外国小跑车
Now what you need is one of those little foreign sports cars that he drives.
# The look of love #
# ls in your eyes... #
# ...The look your heart... #
我好像在哪里见过你
Haven't l seen you before?
# ...Can't disguise... #
也许吧
Maybe.
两年前我替少女杂志拍过封面
A couple years ago, l was on the cover of Seventeen. Yeah.
你是模特儿雪洛
You're that model, right? Cheryl. Yes.
男生都在置物柜贴你的照片
The guys used to put your picture on their lockers.
停在门口的跑车是你的？
lsn't that your silver car l saw parked out front?
对，其中一辆
Yeah. One of them.
# Well, it takes my breath away... #
我能跟你要签名吗？
So, think l could get an autograph?
# ...l can hardly wait to hold you #
# Feel my arms around you... #
你房间有笔吗？
Do you have a pen in your room? # ...How long l have waited... #
# You've got the look of love #
# lt's on your face #
# A look that time can't erase...#
# ...Be mine tonight... #
你这种男人要什么有什么
Man like you can buy anything he wants.
# ...Let this be just the start #
# Of so many nights like this... #
你却到礼品店买一副扑克牌
He buys a deck of cards at the hotel gift shop. # ...And then seal it with a kiss... #
你想看我变魔术吗？
Well, you want to see a card trick? # ...l can hardly wait to hold you... #
这副牌多少钱？
How much did these cards cost?
不晓得，5毛5吧
# ...Feel my arms around you... # Oh, 55 cents, l think. # ...Waited just to love you... #
如果礼品店有卖我的话…
And if they sold me downstairs at the hotel gift shop...
你顺意付多少钱？
how much would you pay? l'm sor...
抱歉，付钱买什么？
l'm sorry, how mu... how much would l pay for what?
共度春宵
The entire night.
你肯出多少让我陪你一整晚？
How much would you pay me for the entire night?
雪洛，我不晓得耶
Cheryl, l... l really don't know.
# ...l can hardly wait to hold you... #
别害怕
Don't be scared.
# ...How long l have waited... #
出个价钱
Make me an offer.
# ...Now that l have found you #
# Don't ever go... #
300 ? $300?
想得美
Go fish.
500 ? Uh, $500?
想得美
Go fish.
$600.
想得美！
Go fish.
1千块钱
$1 ,000.
好吧
Okay.
1千元
$1 ,000.
好吧
Okay.
我马上回来
l'll be right back.
等等，你上哪儿？
Wait a second. Where are you going?
到楼下兑现支票
l'm going downstairs to cash a check.
半夜3点到哪儿兑现1千元？
You think this hotel is going to cash a $1 ,000 check at 3:00am?
这是纽约储贷银行本票 就像是黄金，一定能兑现
lt's a New York Savings and Loan check. lt's like gold. They'll cash it.
他们一定会起疑心，给我看
Don't you think they might get a little suspicious? Let me see that.
这是现金支票，签个名给我
lt's a cashier's check. Endorse it over to me.
不行
No. l couldn't do that.
这是1千4，我们说好1千
See, this check is for $1 ,400. We agreed upon $1 ,000.
我找你400块钱
Why don't l give you back $400
你把支票给我
and you give me that check?
这样更好
Even better.
# The look of love #
# ls in your eyes... #
这件是谁的？
Does this belong to anybody?
# Mele Kalikimaka is the thing to say... #
# On a bright Hawaiian Christmas Day... #
我是韩瑞提，圣诞快乐
This is Hanratty. Merry Christmas.
你好，卡尔
FRANK: Hello, Carl. Hello.
贝瑞艾伦，秘勤局
# ...That we send to you, from the land... # Barry Allen, Secret Service.
我花了几个小时在找你
l've been trying to track you down now for the last couple of hours.
你要什么？
What do you want?
我要为洛杉矶的事向你道歉
l wanted to apologize for what happened out in Los Angeles.
不，别向我道歉
Uh-uh, uh-uh. No, no, you don't apologize to me.
你在耶诞夜也加班吗？
Do you always work on Christmas Eve, Carl?
我自愿加班…
l volunteered
让有家人的同事提早回家
so men with families could go home early.
那天我看到你戴婚戒 我以为你有家庭
Looked like you were wearing a wedding ring out in Los Angeles. l thought maybe you had a family.
我没有
No. No family.
你想跟我聊…
You want to talk to me...
就面对面聊
let's talk face-to-face.
好吧
All right.
我在史督威森饭店3113房
l'm at my suite at the Stuyvesant Arms, room 31 13.
我一早就到赌城度周末
ln the morning, l leave for Las Vegas for the weekend.
你又想骗我吗？
You think you're going to get me again?
你才不去赌城，你也没在饭店
You're not going to Vegas. You're not in the Stuyvesant Arms. You'd love for me
你想骗我在耶诞夜派一堆探员 冲进那家饭店破门而入…
to send out 20 agents Christmas Eve we barge into your hotel, knock down the door
让我们出大糗
so you can make fools out of us all.
我很遗憾让你出糗，是真的
l'm really sorry if l made a fool out of you. l really am. Uh-uh, no.
才怪，你一点也不遗憾
No, listen, l really am. No, no, you-you do not feel sorry for me.
老实说，我知道是你 我没抓到你，但是我知道
The truth is, l knew it was you. Now maybe l didn't get the cuffs on you, but l knew.
你爱怎么说就怎么说
Ah, people only know what you tell them, Carl.
告诉我，秘勤局的贝瑞艾伦
Well, then tell me this, Barry Allen, Secret Service.
你怎么知道我不看你的皮夹？
How did you know l wouldn't look in your wallet?
跟洋塞队总是赢球一样
The same reason the Yankees always win.
大家一直盯着他们的帅制服
Nobody can keep their eyes off the pinstripes.
洋塞队有全垒打王才赢球
The Yankees win because they have Mickey Mantle.
没有人会看他们的制服
No one ever bets on the uniform.
你确定吗？
You sure about that, Carl?
我只确定一点
l'll tell you what l am sure of.
你一定会被捕
You're going to get caught.
不管怎样，这是数学定律 就像在赌城
One way or another, it's a mathematical fact. lt's-lt's like Vegas.
庄家一定赢
The House always wins.
很抱歉，我得走了
Well, Carl, l'm sorry, but l have to go.
你不是打来道歉的，对吧？
Ah. You didn't call just to apologize, did you?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你找不到别人聊天
You... you... you have no one else to call.
# ...Morn and night... #
# ...Doo-lang, doo-lang, doo-lang... #
# The one with the wavy hair... #
你要续杯吗？
More coffee, sir?
贝瑞艾伦
你是收藏家吗？ 收藏什么？
Are you a collector? Of what?
《宇宙光俘虏》 《黄金巨人国》
''Captives of the Cosmic Ray,'' ''The Big Freeze'' ''Land of the Golden Giants.''
我全都有 你在说什么？
l've got them all. What are you talking about?
贝瑞艾伦
Barry Allen.
闪电侠
The Flash.
小子，回来
Wait, kid, kid, kid.
你是说漫画吗？
You mean like the comic book?
对，闪电侠的真名是贝瑞艾伦
Yeah, the comic book. When he's not The Flash. That's his name, Barry Allen.
谢谢你
Thank you.
听好了，他看漫画！
Now get this: He reads comic books.
贝瑞艾伦就是闪电侠！
Comic books! Barry Allen is The Flash!
慢点，你在说什么？ 嫌犯只是个少年
FOX: Carl, slow down. Slow down. l don't know what the hell you're talking about. He's a kid. Our unsub is a kid.
他没有案底，指纹比对没用
That's why we couldn't match his prints. That's why he doesn't have a record.
跟纽约警局联络 寻找每个逃家少年
Now, l want you to contact NYPD for every all-points juvenile runaways in New York City.
别忘了机场，他到处旅行
And don't forget the airports. He's been kiting checks all over the country.
为什么是纽约？ 洋塞队！
But why New York? The Yankees!
他提到洋塞队！
He said something about the Yankees!
找到第几家了？
HANRATTY: So where are we on the list?
第53家，艾巴奈尔
FOX: Number 53, ''Abagnahlee.''
早安，我们是FBI探员
HANRATTY: Good morning, ma'am. We're the FBl agents who called.
我在等你们
Yes, l've been waiting.
饿了吧，我准备了莎莉蛋糕
l hope you're all hungry. l put out the Sara Lee.
我先生杰克是律师
My husband Jack is a lawyer.
你前任丈夫呢，艾太太？
What about your first husband, Mrs. ''Abagnahlee''?
请你们叫我邦恩太太
Abagnale, but l prefer to be called Barnes.
“法兰克威康艾巴奈尔” 他服过役
''Frank William Abagnale.'' lt says here he was in the service.
你们在二次大战认识吗？
Did... Did you two meet during the war?
对，我住在法国小村庄蒙瑞榭
Yeah, l lived in a very small village in France-- Montrichard-- the kind of place
那儿的人没听过莎莉蛋糕
where they never heard of Sara Lee.
请用
Help yourselves.
莎莉蛋糕，人人爱吃
''Nobody doesn't like Sara Lee.''
你们报案协寻一名逃家少年 小法兰克艾巴奈尔
You filled out a missing person's report for a runaway juvenile by the name of Frank Abagnale Jr.
法兰克没事吧？
ls Frankie okay?
他用大通银行帐户开芭乐票
You're aware of the fact that he wrote some checks on a closed account at Chase Manhattan Bank?
我知道，警察说他是坏人
Oh, yes. The police think he's some type of criminal.
他犯下重刑罪
What he did was a felony, Mrs. Barnes.
只有1千元
lt was $1 ,000.
现在的小孩都在嗑药打警察
Half the kids his age are on dope throwing rocks at police
我儿子犯点小错就来吓我
and they scared me to death because my son made a little mistake.
十七岁少年也得吃饭…
Huh. A 1 7-year-old... boy has to eat
找地方住呀
has to have a place to sleep.
我们了解
We understand, ma'am.
你有他的照片吗？
Would you happen to have a picture of your son?
我有他的旧班刊
Oh, yes. l have his old yearbook.
好吧
Okay. Okay, okay, we, uh...
我们要向所有分局发出通报
we need to send out an all-office teletype.
嫌犯是法兰克艾巴奈尔十七岁！
Our unsub's name is Frank Abagnale Jr., age 1 7.
法兰克惹了麻烦吗？
ls Frankie okay? ls he in trouble?
令郎在伪造支票
Ma'am, l'm sorry to have to tell you: Your son is forging checks.
伪造支票？等等！事情好解决
Forging checks? Wait! l'm sure we can take care of that.
我在教会做事
l am working part-time at the church now.
他欠多少钱我都会还清
Just tell me how much he owes and l'll pay you back.
到目前为止是130万元
So far, it's about $1 .3 million.
# Girl, you really got me goin' #
# You got me so l don't know what l'm doin' #
河湾公寓 亚特兰大市，乔治亚州
Riverbend Apartments Atlanta, Georgia # Yeah, you really got me goin' #
梅兰妮，你好
# You got me so l can't sleep at night... # Hi, Melanie, how are you?
在屋子里要用烟灰缸
When you're in the house, please, just use an ashtray.
好棒的小火锅哦！
Frank, this fondue is so good!
很好，拿去 棒呆了，我最爱香槟！
Great. Here, take this for me. Ooh, good! l love Moet! # Oh, yeah... #
Hey. How are you?
# You really got me goin' #
# You got me goin', got me goin' and goin'... #
小詹，拜托！别碰我的音响
James, James, please! Just stay away from the hi-fi system, all right?
这是高档货，别乱来
lt's reel-to-reel. You can't wind it like that. # Don't ever set me free... #
拜托！这是意大利名牌！
Christ! Terry! This is ltalian knit!
小心点！ 那只是件衣服！
Watch where you're going! lt's just a shirt, man!
法兰克！快来呀！
Frank! Come quick!
兰斯跌伤了脚！
Lance just fell into the conversation pit!
抱歉，请问兰斯在哪里？
Excuse me, you know where Lance Applebaum is?
谢谢
Thank you.
这些瓶子要贴标签！
DOCTOR: These bottles need to be labeled when you pick them up.
不贴很危险
Do you understand how dangerous this is? Do you?
别一直哭，说你不会再犯
Don't stand there crying, just nod your head and tell me you won't do it again.
擦干眼泪回去工作
Now dry up and get back to work.
Dr. Blair, Dr. Blair
Dr. Sherwood Blair.
你没事吧？
Hey, hey... you okay?
他叫我拿装血的瓶子
He told me to pick up the blood,
可是他没叫我贴标签
so l did, but he never told me to label it.
没事了，别哭
Hey, it's okay. Stop crying.
你叫什么？
What's your name?
布兰黛
-Brenda. -Brenda.
布兰黛，别担心
Brenda, l wouldn't worry about it. You know, these doctors
别理那些医生
you know, they don't know everything.
这是我第一个礼拜上班
lt's my first week and l think they're going to fire me.
他们一定会炒我鱿鱼
没有人会炒你鱿鱼
No, no, nobody's going to fire you, Brenda.
我打赌你一定很称职
l bet you're good at your job.
才没有
No, l'm not.
如果我请你查我朋友的状况…
Yeah, l bet if l asked you to check on the status of my friend Lance Applebaum
你一定马上就查到
that you could do that for me in a second. Nurse Fitzsimmons to Recovery.
Nurse Fitzsimmons to Recovery.
兰斯跌伤脚踝
Mr. Applebaum fractured his ankle.
艾医师正在为他进行治疗
Dr. Ashland is treating him in exam room seven.
瞧，很好吧
You see that? No problem.
这是急诊室病历
This is the emergency chart.
你看到蓝星吗？ 这代表病人经过诊断
See that blue star there? That means that the patient has been diagnosed.
他接受治疗后就打红圈，瞧
And then, after he's been treated we put a red circle here, see?
你喜欢你的牙套吗？
How do you like those braces?
还可以吧
l guess they're all right.
我的去年才拿掉
l got mine off last year.
我好讨厌牙套，我只戴下面
Boy, l hated them. They were bottoms.
拿掉还得戴护牙胶
You know, l still got to wear my mouth guard.
你的牙齿很好看
You have really nice teeth.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
你笑起来也很美
And you have a pretty smile.
Custodial to cafeteria.
是真的，你戴牙套很好看
No, l mean it. l really think those braces look good on you.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
布兰黛
Brenda.
是
Yeah.
这家医院在请人吗？
Do you know if they're hiring here at the hospital?
我不知道耶，你想做什么？
l'm not sure. What do you want to do?
我是个医生
l'm a doctor.
亲爱的爸…
FRANK: Dear Dad;
我决定不再飞来飞去
l've decided to get off the road for awhile.
我在医院上夜班，认识一些人
l've taken a night job at a hospital and met some really nice people.
脚踏实地的感觉真好 每天都睡同一张床
Feels good to have my feet on the ground to wake up in the same bed every night.
也许我会找一个人安顿下来
Who knows, maybe l'll even find someone to settle down with.
“哈佛医学院”，第一名毕业
Harvard Medical School... top of your class.
“南加州儿童医院”
Southern California Children's Hospital.
你的资历很好，康纳医师
Well, that's a pretty impressive resume, Dr. Conners
只可惜…
but unfortunately, uh... the only thing l need
我们只需要…
is a... an emergency room supervisor
大夜班的急诊室主任医师
for my midnight to 8:00am shift
管六名住院医师和二十个护士
someone to baby-sit six interns and 20 nurses
但是
but, uh...
我猜你一定没有兴趣
Hell, l doubt that, uh, you would be interested in that.
以前我都能亲自挑选护士
in the past they've always let me choose my own nurses.
康纳利医师
Dr. Connelly?
哈里斯医师 在
Dr. Harris? Present.
艾希兰医师
Dr. Ashland?
康纳医师？
Dr. Conners...
你每天都要点名吗？
You gonna take roll every night?
是的
Uh, yes, l will, Dr. Ashland
你迟到别忘了带家长的信
and if you're going to be late, l suggest you bring a note.
贝丝护士
Miss Basmann.
梅丝护士
Miss Mace.
史托护士
Miss Strong.
在
Here.
布朗护士
Nurse Brown.
桑佛护士
-Nurse Sanford? -Here.
每四小时注射三十毫克可待因
30 milligrams of codeine
每分钟六十滴直到了解病情
every four hours. Run the plasma at 60 drops a minute until we calculate the fluid requirements.
你估计灼伤程度是什么？
What do you estimate the degree and extent of the burns, Kildare?
身上有二成是二度到三度灼伤
DR. KlLDARE: Second and third-degree burns over about 20 percent of the body surface.
你同意吗？ 我同意，把他送到儿童病房
Do you concur? l concur. Let's get him up to Pediatrics.
法兰克康纳医学博士
Nurse Hopp to the Nurses' Station South.
你好，布兰黛
Hello, Brenda.
嗨，康纳医师
Hi, Dr. Conners.
- 谢谢签名  - 谢谢
You need to sign these. Thank you.
你没注意到什么吗？ 你拿掉牙套了！
Do you notice anything different about me, Doctor? -You got your braces off! -Yeah! Come here. Let me see.
我整晚都在暗示你！
l've been trying to show you all night!
挺好的
Wow. Good job. Yeah?
会不会痛？我拿掉时怪怪的
So, did it hurt when they took them off? Mine felt so weird after.
我一直用舌头舔牙齿！
Mm, l keep rubbing my tongue over them.
好滑哦
l can't stop. They're so slippery.
感觉很棒吧？ 是啊，棒呆了
lt feels good, though, doesn't it? Yeah, it feels incredible.
天啊！
Oh, my.
对不起
l'm... l'm sorry.
康纳医师请到急诊室
Dr. Conners to the ER. Dr. Conners to the ER.
你要去吗？
Shouldn't you go? No. No, no.
不去 急诊室有值班医生，没问题
They have a staff doctor in the emergency ward. We'll be fine.
也许他在手术室
What if he's in surgery?
你真的觉得我该去吗？
Do you really think l have to go?
在这儿
Oh. ln here, Dr. Conners.
各位，有什么问题？
Gentlemen, what, uh... what seems to be the problem?
骑单车摔倒 膝盖骨下五寸的胫骨破裂
Bicycle accident. Fractured tibia about five inches below the patella.
哈里斯医师
-Dr. Harris. -Yes?
你同意吗？
Do you concur?
同意什么？
C... Concur with what, sir?
艾希兰医师说的，你同意吗？
With what Dr. Ashland just said. Do you... Do you concur?
这是单车意外，小男孩说了
Uh... well, it was a bicycle accident. Um, the boy told us.
你同意吗？
So you concur? Concur? Uh...
应该照X光，缝合伤口 然后打石膏
l think we should take an X ray then stitch him up and put him in a walking cast.
很好，非常好
That's very good, Dr. Ashland. Very good.
你们不需要我
Well, you don't seem to have much need for me.
继续吧
Carry on.
我搞砸了，对吧？
l blew it, didn't l?
我干嘛不说同意呢？
Why didn't l concur? Dr. Henning, call extension 219.
把这儿当自个儿家！
FRANK SR.: Make yourself at home!
法兰克艾巴奈尔
Frank Abagnale Sr.
你不是警察
You're not a cop.
联邦调查局特别探员韩瑞提
Special Agent Hanratty, FBl.
你不是警察，我房东说的
You're not a cop. My landlord said you were not a cop.
你要抓我就让我穿另一套西装
Well, if you're going to arrest me l'd like to put on a different suit
如果可以的话… 我不是来抓你
if that's okay with you. No, no, l'm not here to arrest you.
我来找你儿子，他有麻烦
l'm looking for your son. He's in trouble.
你知道他的下落吗？
Do you know where he is?
我说出来你保证不告诉他妈
lf l tell you where he is will you promise not to tell his mother?
好
Sure.
他伪造身份证加入海军陆战队
Frank made up a fake l.D. and enlisted in the Marine Corps.
他正在打越战
He's over in Vietnam right now.
他大老远跑到世界另一头
That kid is halfway around the world
冒着生命危险打共匪
crawling through the damn jungle fighting the Communists, so...
别跑来我家说他犯了罪…
please, don't come to my home and call my boy a criminal
我没这么说，我只说他有麻烦
because that kid has more guts... l never said he was a criminal, Mr. Abagnale. l said he was in trouble.
你想谈就打给我，我的名片
lf you'd like to give me a call and talk, here's my number.
亲爱的爸，
河湾公寓，亚特兰大市
你没有小孩吧？
You're not a father, are you?
什么？
Pardon me?
如果你有就知道
lf you were a father, you'd know.
我绝不会出卖我儿子
l would never give up my son.
是的，我了解
Yes, sir. l understand.
西恩，抄下来…
Sean, Sean, now get this:
“河湾公寓，兰道街415号 乔治亚州，亚特兰大市”
''Riverbend Apartments 415 Landover, Atlanta, Georgia.'' Atlanta, Georgia.
我要赶到机场 四小时后见，再见！
Yeah, l'm on my way to the airport. l'll meet the team in, uh, in four hours. Bye-bye.
来，没关系
Come on, it's okay.
别哭了
You don't have to cry.
对不起！我办不到
l'm sorry. l'm so sorry, Frank. l can't do this.
听我说
Brenda, listen to me.
我不在乎你是处女
l don't care if you're a virgin, all right?
我可以等
Really, l can wait.
我不是处女
l'm not a virgin.
我两年前堕过胎
l had an abortion two years ago.
我爸妈请朋友帮我拿掉小孩
My parents had a friend do it
我爸的高尔夫球友
a man that my father plays golf with.
筝我身体好了就被赶出家门
And then, when l got better, they kicked me out of the house.
我堕过胎就不能当他们的女儿！
l had an abortion and l wasn't their daughter anymore. Hey...
对不起，请你别生我的气
l'm so sorry. Please don't be mad at me. Please, please, don't be mad at me.
不会
No, no.
别生我的气
Please don't be mad at me. Shh. Now... what if...
我去找你爸妈谈
what if l spoke to your parents, right?
也许我能替你说服他们
May-Maybe l can straighten things out, huh?
我每次问他们都不准我回去
Well, l ask them all the time but they said l still can't come home.
我爸是个律师
And my daddy's... a lawyer.
布兰黛
Brenda...
要是你跟医生订婚呢？
what if you were engaged to a doctor?
这样会不会比较好？
Will that change anything?
什么？
What?
我去找你爸妈…
What if l went to your parents...
我找你爸谈…
and l spoke to your father...
请他把你嫁给我？
and l asked permission to marry you?
空无一人 没有人在家
lt's empty. Nobody here.
纽奥良
New Orleans
康大夫，你是路德会信徒吗？
Dr. Conners, are you Lutheran?
是的，我是
Yes, l-l am a Lutheran,
请叫我法兰克
but, please, call me Frank.
那就请你饭前祷告
Frank, would you like to say grace?
除非你不想
Unless you're not comfortable.
我很乐意
Absolutely.
两只老鼠掉进一桶鲜奶油
Two little mice fell into a bucket of cream.
第一只很快就放弃然后淹死
The first mouse quickly gave up and drowned
第二只拼命挣扎 把鲜奶油变成牛油…
but the second mouse, he struggled so hard that he eventually churned that cream into butter
然复爬出去
and he walked out.
阿门
-Amen. -Amen.
好感人哦
Amen. Oh, that was beautiful.
小老鼠把鲜奶油变成牛油
The mouse, he churned that cream into butter.
没错
That's right. That's pretty good.
谢谢
Thank you.
你决定要到哪家医院吗？
Frank, have you decided which hospital you want to work at here in New Orleans? Well, um, to be quite honest
老实说，我想回去当律师
l'm thinking about getting back into law.
你到底是医生还是律师？
Oh, my! Are you a doctor or a lawyer?
我念医学院前考到律师执照
Before l went to medical school, l passed the bar in California.
我在加州执业一年后决定…
l practiced law for one year
我何不当一个小儿科医师？
then l decided why not try my hand at pediatrics?
你真是充满惊喜
You're just full of surprises.
是啊
Yeah. Oh, my.
医生和律师，她钓到金龟婿了
A doctor and a lawyer. Well, l'd say that Brenda hit the jackpot.
你在哪里念法律系？
Where did you go to law school?
柏克莱
Uh, Berkeley.
Berkley, Berkley. Oh, my gosh.
你也念那儿，不是吗？
lsn't that where you went, Daddy?
法兰克可以替你做事
Maybe Frank could come work for you, Roger.
你老说助理检察官有多难找
You're always saying how hard it is to find Assistant Prosecutors.
爸，他可以吗？
Could he, Daddy? Could he, please? Could he come work with you, please?
何教授还在那儿教书吗？
Was that snake Hollingsworth still teaching there when you went through Berkley?
何教授
Hollingsworth.
那个怪老头，对吧？
Yes. Grumpy old Hollingsworth, right?
比以前更怪
l tell you. Meaner than ever.
他的狗呢？
And that dog of his?
他的小狗叫什么名字？
Tell me, Frank, what was the name of his little dog?
很抱歉
l'm sorry. Uh...
他的狗死了
The dog was dead.
真不幸
How unfortunate.
是啊
Yeah.
医生、律师、路德会信徒…
A doctor, a lawyer, a Lutheran...
你到底是什么人？
So what are you, Frank?
你打算向我女儿求婚
'Cause l think you're about to ask for my daughter's hand in marriage
我有权知道
and l have a right to know.
知道什么？
Know what, sir?
实话
The truth.
告诉我实话
Tell me the truth, Frank.
你来这儿干嘛？
What are you doing here?
你怎么会跟布兰黛在一起？
What is a man like you doing with Brenda?
如果你要我把女儿嫁给你
lf you want my blessing if you want my daughter
就乖乖跟我说实话
l'd like to hear it from you now.
事实是…
The truth is, sir, that...
事实是这样…
The truth is that...
我不是医生，也不是律师
l'm not a doctor, l'm not a lawyer...
我更不是机师
l'm not an airline pilot.
我什么都不是
l'm... l'm nothing, really.
我只是一个爱上你女儿的少年
l'm-l'm-l'm just a kid who's in love with your daughter.
不是
No.
你知道你是什么吗？
You know what you are?
你是个痴心汉
You're a romantic.
你失去了爱人就什么也不是
Men like us are nothing without the women we love.
老实说，我也是个痴心汉
l must confess, l'm guilty of the same foolish whimsy. l proposed to Carol after five dates
我约卡萝五次后就跟她求婚 当时我只是个穷小子
with two nickels in my pockets and holes in my shoes
但她是我的真命天女
because l knew she was the one.
尽管说吧
So go ahead, Frank.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
你要问我什么就问吧
Ask the question you came here to ask me.
先生
Sir, uh, uh...
我要怎样才能考到律师执照？
w-what would l have to do to take the bar here in New Orleans?
不对，另一个问题
No, the... the other question.
请进去那儿考试
WOMAN: Right through that door.
祝好运，康纳先生
Good luck, Mr. Conners.
谢谢
Thank you.
12月26日，1969年
December 26, 1969
法兰克
Hey, Frank...
我一直搞不懂
you know what l could never figure out?
你怎么作弊考到律师执照？
How did you cheat on the bar exam in Louisiana?
这重要吗？
Why? What's the difference?
你找了枪手吗？ 我要坐很久的牢
Someone else took the test for you, didn't they? Carl, l'm going to prison for a long time.
说真的，这重要吗？
Seriously, what's the difference?
我只是问问而已
lt's a simple question.
你要吃那个泡芙吗？
Are you going to eat that eclair?
要，我留着待会吃
Yeah. l'm saving it for later.
跟我分，好吗？
Well, you want to split it with me?
不好
No.
分我一半我就告诉你
Give me half that eclair and l'll tell you.
我迟早会知道
l'm going to figure it out sooner or later.
你要在公司法部门做事
You'll be working under Phillip Rigby in corporate law.
安顿下来，整理办公桌
Why don't you settle in, organize your desk?
我们十二点半和司法部长 还有麦肯森州长吃午饭
Thank you. We're having lunch at 12:30 with the Attorney General and Governor McKeithen.
亲身莅临
Himself.
州长！
The Governor.
名字没拼错吗？
Did we spell it right?
没错
You sure did.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
谢谢 欢迎加入
Thank you, sir. Welcome aboard. Now...
请你看这张照片
Look at this photograph, Mr. Stewart.
这是约克在陈见处的照片
lt's a photograph of Prentice York where they found him, dead.
这是放大的照片
Now, here is an enlargement of part of that photograph.
这是被告支票上的签名的照片
This is a photograph of the defendant's signature on a canceled check.
这是放大的照片 笔迹跟他写的信一模一样
Now, here is an enlargement of that same signature which matches
他在信上…
the signature on the letters that he wrote to Mrs. Simon
讨论如何诈欺本州
which discuss the possibility of defrauding the great State of Louisiana.
庭上、各位陪审团员…
Your Honor, ladies and gentlemen of the jury
这就是被告说谎的确切证据
this is irrefutable evidence that the defendant is, in fact, lying.
康纳先生，这是审前听证会
Mr. Conners, this is a preliminary hearing.
根本就没有被告
There is no... defendant.
也没有陪审团
There is no... jury.
只有我
lt's just me.
小子…”'
Son...
你是不是秀逗了？
what in the hell is wrong with you?!
那是米奇吗？
-ls that Mitch? Roger!
是耶！
lt's Mitch!
我都忘了时间
Oh, my, l lost all track of time.
今晚在现场一起欢唱的是…
As studio guests for the sing-along tonight
纽约圣蒙尼卡教会儿童合唱团
we have the children's choir of St. Monica's Church in New York City.
大家一起跟着唱爱尔兰民谣！
Won't you join them and the gang in a few songs for the lrish? Everybody! # Has anybody here seen Kelly? #
# K, E, double L, Y #
# Has anybody here seen Kelly? #
# Have you seen him smile? #
# Sure his hair is red, and his eyes are blue #
# And he's lrish through and through #
# Has anybody here seen Kelly #
# Kelly from the Emerald lsle? #
# Has anybody here seen Kelly? #
# K, E, double L, Y #
# Have you seen him smile? #
# Sure his hair is red, and his eyes are blue #
# And he's lrish through and through #
# Has anybody here seen Kelly... #
# Embrace me #
# My sweet embraceable you #
# You irreplaceable you #
# Just one look at you #
# My heart grew tipsy in me #
# You and you alone #
# Bring out the gypsy in me #
# l love all #
# The many charms about you #
# Above all #
# l want my arms about you... #
爸？
Dad.
# ...Don't be a naughty baby... #
你跑来干嘛？
What are you doing here?
我来看你
l... l-l came to see you.
# ...My sweet embraceable... #
你怎么穿成这样？
What are you doing dressed like this?
我当了邮差
l took a job. A government job.
你看到吗？你有好律师吗？
You see what l'm doing? Do you have a good lawyer?
我现在就是个律师
Well... l sort of am a lawyer now.
你看看，国税局要更多钱
Look at this letter. The lRS wants more.
我付了他们两笔罚金
l had a deal with them: two penalties.
他们会得无厌还要榨我钱
They ate the cake, now they want the crumbs.
我要告他们
l want to sue them.
他们不放过我
Now they want the crumbs.
坐吧
They... Here, sit down.
他们想吓我、威胁我 你知道吗？
They're trying to scare me, intimidate me. You know what?
你知道吗？
You know what?
我要让他们追着我跑…
l'll make them chase me...
追一辈子！
for the rest of their lives.
见到你真好
Hey, it's great to see you, Daddy.
坐下来，我给你看样东西
Listen, sit down, l... l want to show you something.
我是来给你这个
l came here to give you this.
这是我的订婚喜帖
lt's an invitation to an engagement party.
爸，我要结婚了
Daddy, l'm getting married.
你相信吗？
Can you believe that? l'm getting married.
你什么都不用担心
You don't need to worry about anything now, Dad.
我要买新车、买房子…
Listen, l'm getting a brand-new Cadillac. l'm getting a $60,000 house.
帮你把一切买回来
l'm-l'm getting it all back.
珠宝首饰和皮草 他们夺走的我都要讨回来
All-All the jewelry, all the furs, everything, Dad. Everything they took from us, l'm going to get it back.
妈见过你这样吗？
has Ma seen you dressed like this?
见过，她来拿一些箱子
Yeah, she came to pick up some boxes.
没关系
That's okay, that's okay, you know why?
她也要来参加婚礼
'Cause she... she's going to the wedding with us. l'm going to get you a brand-new suit, Dad.
我会送你一套新西装
l'm getting you a brand-new suit.
三排扣西装，你一定会很帅
One of those Manhattan Eagle, three-button, black pearl suits. You'll look great.
挺好的，她不会见我
Those are nice. Yeah. She won't see me.
你有打给她吗？
Well, have you tried to call her? Uh-uh.
现在打给她
Why don't... why don't you call her right now?
现在就打给她呀
Dad, why don't you call her right now? Here.
爸
Dad,
为了我打给她
just call her. Call her for me.
我买了两张头等舱机票…
You call her, and you tell her l have two first-class tickets to go see her son's wedding...
你妈嫁给我朋友杰克邦恩 他们住在长岛
Your mother's married now, to my friend Jack Barnes. They have a house in Long lsland.
联邦探员来找过我
l had an FBl agent come see me.
你吓到他们，那家伙很怕
You got their number, son. The guy looked scared.
你让美国政府落荒而逃
The United States government, champ, running for the hills.
一步登天！
Pow! To the moon!
爸，我不玩了
Dad... it's over.
我决定罢手
l'm going to stop now. But y-you've...
他们永远都抓不到你
They're never going to catch you, Frank.
她不会的！她怎么能这么对你？
-Dad, she wouldn't do that. -Why won't you sit down? -Why would she do that to you? -Come on, sit.
坐下来喝一杯，我是你老爸耶
Come on, sit with me. Have a drink. l'm your father.
那就叫我罢手，叫我罢手
Then ask me to stop. Then ask me to stop.
你不能罢手
You can't stop.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
说呀，你要去哪里？
Come on, Frank, where are you going?
你今晚要去哪里？
Where are you going? Where are you going tonight?
新奇的地方？
Someplace exotic?
你要去哪里？大溪地？夏威夷？
Where are you going tonight? Tahiti, Hawaii?
这是韩瑞提
This is Hanratty.
卡尔
FRANK: Hello, Carl.
耶诞节快乐
Merry Christmas.
你好，康纳大夫
How are you, Dr. Conners?
我不当康纳大夫很久了
Carl, l haven't been Dr. Conners for months now.
我在耶诞夜只能窝在办公室
Well... l'm sitting here in my office on Christmas Eve.
你要什么？
What do you want?
好吧
Okay.
我要这一切都结束
l want it to be over.
我要洗手不干，我要结婚了
Uh... l want it to be over. l'm getting married.
我要安顿下来
You know, l'm settling down.
你偷了4百万元
You've stolen almost $4 million.
你要把它当红包吗？
You think we can just call that a wedding present?
你想脱身没这么容易
Nah, this isn't something you get to walk away from, Frank.
我要跟你停火 不行
l want to call a truce. No truce.
你会被关进大牢 你不会有好下场
You will be caught, you will go to prison. Where did you think this was going?
求求你放过我
Please leave me alone, Carl.
拜托？
Please?
我快抓到你了，对吧？
l'm getting close, aren't l?
所以你才会害怕，我知道…
You're scared because l'm getting close.
你租车，待过查尔斯市
l know you... you rented that car in Shreveport and you stayed in that hotel on Lake Charles.
你想跑就跑
You want to run, be my guest.
但是你的支票不会说谎
Your checks don't lie as well as you do.
别再追我了
Stop chasing me.
办不到
l can't stop.
这是我的职责
lt's my job.
没关系
lt's okay, Carl.
我只是问问
l just thought l'd ask, you know?
圣诞快乐
Hey. Merry Christmas, huh?
我好爱我的工作
l love my job.
好吧
All right
去找路易西安那州 过去两个月的每份报纸
let's get every newspaper we can every newspaper in Louisiana for the last two months.
我们要找什么？
What are we looking for?
订婚启事，名字是康纳
Engagement announcements, name of Conners. Conners?! Come on, Carl, the kid would've
拜托，他早就改名换姓了
changed his name by now.
不会
Mm-mm. He can't change it.
她认为他是康纳
She thinks he's Conners.
他改了名就会失去她
lf he loses the name, he loses the girl. # l can't give you anything #
# But love, baby #
# That's the only thing l have plenty of #
# Baby #
恭喜！ 开心吗？
# Dreamin' a while, schemin' a while... # -Congratulations. -You having a good time?
# ...You're sure to find #
继续跳吧
-# Happiness, and l guess # -Keep dancing, huh?
# All those things you've always pined for... #
看是谁来了
-Oh. -Hi. Oh, me too. Thank you.
我要去上厕所
l'm going to, uh, the little boys' room. -Okay. -Okay.
赶快回来
Hurry back.
晚上好
Good evening.
我是联邦探员韩瑞提
l'm Agent Hanratty with the FBl.
我们想跟男主人私下谈谈
We'd like to have a few quiet words with your host, if possible.
我去找他
MAN: l'll get him.
这里请
Right over there, sir. -Hi, Roger. How are you? -Hi, Vin.
你们好，我是罗杰史托
Good evening, gentlemen. l'm Roger Strong.
联邦探员卡尔韩瑞提 这是安探员和福探员
Carl Hanratty, FBl. This is Agents Amdursky and Fox. Sorry to crash your party, sir.
不好意思打搅了 不会，我能帮什么忙？
Not at all. What can l do for you?
可以的话我想见见新郎
lf it's not too much trouble, l'd like to meet the groom.
有麻烦吗？
ls there a problem?
法兰克
-Frank! Frank!
法兰克，你看这么多支票
Can you hold all these? Yeah. Come here.
都是我爸朋友送的礼金…
They're checks. They're from my dad's friends. They're for us, so we can start a new life... Hey!
你在干嘛？怎么了？
What are you doing? What's wrong?
我们得离开
We have to leave. What?!
你爱我，对吧？
Brenda, you love me, right? Yes.
不管怎样你都爱我
l mean, you'd love me no matter what. Yes.
就算我生病或有别的名字
l mean, you'd love me whether l was sick or whether l was poor or even if l had a different name.
你哪来的那么多钱？
Frank, where'd you get all that money? Brenda, listen. A name, right?
名字并不重要
A name, it doesn't matter.
我跟你在一起是法兰克康纳 但是每个人都有秘密
My name is Frank Conners, right? -That's who l am with you. -Yes. But-but we all have secrets.
我的秘密是有时候我会用假名 法兰克泰勒
You know, sometimes when l travel l use the name Frank Taylor. That-That's my secret.
法兰克布莱克，这不重要
-Frank Taylor?! -Yeah, Frank Taylor, you know? -Frank Black. -Frank Black?! Yeah, it doesn't matter.
你为什么说这些？
Why are you saying all this?
我不想再骗你
Brenda... Brenda, l don't want to lie to you anymore.
我不是医生，我没念过医学院
All right? l'm not a doctor. l never went to medical school.
我也不是律师或路德会信徒
l'm not a lawyer or a Harvard graduate or a Lutheran.
我一年半前逃家时才十六岁
Brenda, l ran away from home a year and a half ago when l was 16. Frank...
法兰克
Frank?
你不是路德会信徒？
You're not a Lutheran? Brenda... you see all this money?
你看，我有更多钱
You see all this money? l have more.
我有好多钱
l have plenty more.
够我们舒服过一辈子
l have enough money to last us for the rest of our lives -Look.
别逗我了！
Frank, stop teasing me.
你是法兰克康纳，二十八岁…
You're Frank Conners. You're Frank Conners, and you're 28 years old and...
你干嘛要骗我？
Why would you lie to me? -Brenda, Brenda... -l want to know your name.
我想知道你真正的名字
-Listen to me, Brenda. -Tell me your name.
相信我，我们住哪儿都行
We can live anywhere we want but you have to trust me, Brenda.
你相信我吗？你爱我吗？
-Do you trust me? -Yes. -Do you love me, Brenda? -Yes.
我爱你
-You love me? -l love you.
孩子的妈
Excuse me, Mother.
这是韩先生，内人卡萝
Honey, this is Mr. Hanratty. My wife Carol.
您是… 敝姓韩
-Oh, Mister...? -Hanratty, ma'am. -Ratty. -Yes.
你看到法兰克或布兰黛吗？
Have you seen Frank or Brenda?
他们在楼上
l-l think they went upstairs.
法兰克
Frank...
过来
Brenda, come here. Okay,
两天后到迈阿密国际机场找我
in two days, you're going to meet me at Miami lnternational Airport, all right?
筝你爸妈上了床才走 叫一辆计程车
You're going to leave the house after your parents go to sleep. You're going to take a taxicab.
请司机连夜把你送到迈阿密
You give the taxi driver this money right here and you tell him to drive all through the night.
早上十点碰面
Brenda, you're going to leave at 10:00am.
早上十点
-10:00am, all right? -But...
# l never stop #
# Till l get to the top... #
- 哪一间  - 角落那间
Which room, sir? ln the corner.
迈阿密国际机场，说一遍
You have to listen to me, all right? The lnternational Terminal in Miami, all right? Say it.
不管怎样都叫计程车 十点钟赶到那儿
-No matter what... -No matter what... -You're going to take a taxicab. -l will take a taxi.
我一定会到
You're going to be there at 10:00am. l will be there at 10:00am, no matter what.
两天后，布兰黛
-ln two days. -Two days. Two days, Brenda. Two days.
两天后早上十点我一定到
ln two days, l'll be there no matter what, at 10:00am.
答应我，别告诉别人
You're not going to tell anyone, Brenda. You have to promise me, now.
你走之前跟我说你的真名
Frank, please! Before you go, please tell me your name. Please, tell me.
法兰克威康艾巴奈尔
Frank William Abagnale Jr.
迈阿密国际机场
布兰黛
Brenda.
那家伙没来
AMDURSKY: This guy's a no-show. He must've got wise to us.
他今天不来明天也会来
HANRATTY: Maybe he was tipped. lf he's not here today, he'll be tomorrow.
我们会逮到他出境 他没有护照
We'll get him before he leaves the country. He doesn't have a passport.
他都能伪造毕业证书 一定能弄到假护照
For the last six months, he's gone to Harvard and Berkeley. l'm betting he can get a passport.
我们在这儿堵他 他来过这儿，对这儿很熟
So we have all our men waiting for him here in Miami lnternational. He's used it before. He knows the layout.
迈阿密警方派五十位员警轮班
l talked to Miami police; they've offered us 50 uniformed cops in two shifts of 25.
加上我们就有一百人
With our guys, that's almost 100 men in one airport.
要不要到别的地方？ 不要，他会在这儿出境
Don't you think we should spread it around? No, no, this is the exit point.
也许他去了纽约或亚特兰大
Well, how do you know he hasn't rented a car and driven to airports in New York, Atlanta?
我没在纽约或亚特兰大
Because l'm not in New York. l'm not in Atlanta.
我是法兰克劳勃
Yes, this is, uh, Frank Roberts
我要通知所有的大学…
and l'm letting all the universities
泛美航空准备应征空服员
in the area know that Pan Am will be initiating a new recruiting program this year.
我明天会到贵大学
l'll, uh, be stopping by your campus tomorrow morning.
谢谢各位前来
Thank you all very much for coming.
今天我要选出八位美丽小姐…
At the end of the day l'll be choosing eight young ladies
参加泛美…
to be a part of...
空服员训练课程 她们将陪我到欧洲…
...Pan Am's future stewardess flight crew program. Now, these eight young ladies will accompany me
进行两个月的公关旅行…
on a two-month public relations tour through Europe.
然后学会怎么当…
They will discover firsthand what it takes
泛美空服员
to be a Pan American stewardess.
至少要两个人 不，每两个柜台就要一个人
HANRATTY: Give me at least two men... Nah, one man per every two counters. -Mm-hmm. -All right?
安道斯塞？
Amdursky? Yeah?
请员警巡逻入口和出口
Make sure your uniforms are covering the sidewalk entrances and exits.
然后定时查看男厕
Hey... let's have, uh, periodic sweeps of the men's lav. You, here.
我为什么能当空服员？
What qualifies me to be a future stewardess?
我觉得我很友善 我相信我…
Well, l think that l'm really friendly and l can really help out
能让旅客宾至如归…
and, um, make people feel welcome on the plane and...
我们以时速6千英里 在3百英尺高空中飞行
We'll be traveling at 6,000 miles per hour at an altitude of 300 feet.
我都打包好
# All my bags are packed,  #
准备离去
#  l'm ready to go...#
艾琳安德森
llene Anderson.
蜜姬艾克
Miggy Acker.
黛博拉 麦可米兰
Debra Jo McMillan.
坎蒂赫斯顿
Candy Heston. FRANK SlNATRA: # Come fly with me, let's fly, let's fly away #
# lf you can use some exotic booze #
迈阿密国际机场
# There's a bar in far Bombay # # Come fly with me, let's fly, let's fly away #
# Come fly with me, let's float down to Peru #
# ln llama land there's a one-man band #
# And he'll toot his flute for you #
# Come fly with me... #
# ...Let's take off in the blue #
# Once l get you up there #
# Where the air is rarefied #
# We'll just glide starry-eyed #
# Once l get you up there... #
看到那金发美女吗？ 我应该当机师的
You see that blonde out front? l should have been a pilot.
是啊
Exactly. Mr. Carl Hanratty
韩探员，请接听免费电话
please pick up the courtesy telephone.
韩瑞提 你的对讲机不通
Hanratty. AMDURSKY: Carl, your walkie-talkie wasn't working.
J航站前面有人穿泛美制服 坐在白色轿车里面
There's a guy in a Pan Am uniform sitting in a white Coupe DeVille out in front of Terminal J.
那是包机航站，你看到他吗？
That's the charter terminal. Can you get a look at his face?
他戴了机师帽，一定是他
He's got his pilot's cap on. Carl, l think it's him! # ...Just say the words, and we'll beat the birds #
# Down to Acapulco Bay... #
Watch out, watch out, watch out!
# ...lt's perfect for a flying honeymoon, they say... #
法兰克，下车
Out of the car, Frank.
法兰克
Frank?!
下车
Step out of the car!
把手伸出来
Keep your hands where l can see 'em.
别开枪，我只是司机 他给我一百元穿这制服
Don't shoot me! l'm just a driver. A man paid me $100 to wear this uniform
来接人 你要来接谁？
and pick someone up at the airport. Who you picking up? Hey!
韩瑞提
# Pack up, let's fly away. #
七个月后
Seven months later
南美洲、澳洲、新加坡、埃及
HANRATTY: South America, Australia Singapore, Egypt.
这小子完全失去控制
The kid's gone completely out of control.
为什么不通知我？ 没有人接到通知
Why wasn't l called? FOX: Nobody was called, sir.
银行到上礼拜才知道 不可能
The banks didn't know what was happening till last week.
不是伪造支票就不会通知我们
That's impossible. They didn't call 'cause it's not counterfeiting.
他在做什么？ 他在做真的支票
-lt's something else. -Well, what is he doing? He's making real checks, sir.
连航空公司都看不出来 上一张是在＇马德里
These are so perfect the airline didn't know the difference. Last check was cashed in Madrid a week ago.
我猜他还在，我们得马上出发
My guess is he's still there. We have to leave now, sir. Today.
- 去哪？  - 西班牙
Go where?
你要去西班牙？
Spain? You want to go to Spain?
他一定要回去印支票
Well, eventually, he's got to go back to where the checks were printed.
所以他才在欧洲兜圈子
l think that's why he's moving back through Europe. Look at the map, sir. He's making a circle.
他的支票快用完了
He's running out of checks. l know it's a... it's a long shot, sir
这是险招 只要追踪到他就能逮到他
but if we track him from Madrid, sir, we could still catch him.
在这儿逮不到他在那儿也不行
l'm sorry, Carl, if you couldn't catch him here you're not going to catch him there.
我们会让他逃走
But, sir, we're going to let him get away.
不，是你让他逃走
No, Carl, you let him get away.
边缘是… 16分之1寸
A perfect one-16th all the way around. Hmm!
分色很完美
Color separation is flawless.
毫无瑕疵
There's no bleeding. Hmm.
美国没有人做得到
Nobody does work like this in the States.
除了我们
Nobody but us.
这是用什么印的？
HANRATTY: Where was it printed?
这是用旧型印刷机印的… 旧型印刷机
lt was printed on a monster... A monster.
海德堡或艾斯托牌 海德堡
...a Heidelberg, an lstra... Heidelberg.
四色平版印刷机，非常笨重
...a dinosaur, four colors. You can smell the weight.
没加墨水都有两吨重
Two tons, without the ink.
这种印刷术在哪里才有？
Where do they do printing like this?
德国、英国…
Germany, Great Britain...
法国
France. BOTH PRlNTERS: France!
法兰克的母亲来自法国小村庄
France. Frank's mother said the name of a village in France where they didn't have Sara Lee.
她在那儿认识法兰克的父亲 我不记得…
The village where she met Frank's father. Oh, yeah, l don't remember, uh...
有个“M"，蒙什么 蒙什么？
lt started with an M. lt was, uh, ''Mont'' something. ''Mont.'' Mr. Fox?
问题：“你在战时跟你丈夫相识的”
Uh, yes, yes. Question: ''You met your husband during the war?''
回答：“我来自一座法国小村庄 那儿的人没听过莎莉蛋糕”
Answer: ''Yes, l lived in a small village in France. Yeah, right. ''The kind of place where they never heard of Sara Lee.''
跟我说你记下村庄名字
Tell me you wrote down the name of the village, Mr. Fox.
蒙瑞榭
Montrichard.
# Laeti triumphantes #
法国，蒙瑞榭 耶诞夜，1967年
Montrichard, France Christmas Eve 1967 # Venite, venite #
# ln Bethlehem #
# Natum videte #
# Regem angelorum #
# Venite adoremus, Venite adoremus #
# Venite... #
卡尔
Carl?
Carl!
耶诞快乐！
Merry Christmas!
我们老是在圣诞节说话 每年圣诞节我都跟你聊天！
How is it that we're always talking on Christmas, Carl? Every Christmas l'm talking to you!
穿上衬衫，你被捕了
Put your shirt on, Frank. You're under arrest. Hey, are you hungry? Do you want some beans, Carl?
你饿吗？来点豆子？ 这儿有最棒的扁豆
They got the best French beans here. Here, give these a try.
外面有二十几名法国警察
There's two dozen French police officers outside. Carl, l gotta tell you, they're delicious. They wanted to bring you in.
他们想逮你就要靠我这美国人
You want a bite? But they needed the help of an American. Are you hungry? You want a bite?
除非我能亲手铐住你， 否则不会透露你在那里
But l told them l wouldn't bring them to you unless l could put the cuffs on you myself.
你有枪吗？没有？ 没有
Well, you have a gun? You have a gun? -No gun? -No. No gun.
你刚才说什么？
And-and you're... and you're telling me what? There's, uh,
二十几个警察在耶诞夜跑来？
there's two dozen French police officers out there right now on Christmas Eve?
你是这样说的吗？ 对
That's what you're telling me? Yeah.
好吧，这儿没窗户
All right, all right. Well, there's no windows here.
我要到前门看看 不！
l'm going to take a look out the front door. No! No!
我说我会出去打信号 你自己戴上手铐
l told them l'd walk out first and give a signal. Here, you can put these on yourself.
不行！你知道原因吗？
No, l can't do that! l can't do that. You know why?
因为你在唬我 外面根本就没有人
'Cause l think you're full of shit. l don't... l don't think there's anyone else out there.
只有你跟我
l think... l think it's just me and you. That's right.
只有你跟我，你得亲自抓我
l think it's just me and you, and you know what? You're going to have to catch me yourself!
别浪费时间 真高明
l wo... we don't have time for this. Ah, that's good. That's good.
你想要骗我
Tell me what you want me to see, huh?
我不会骗你 你戴了婚戒
l wouldn't lie to you. Look, you're wearing a wedding ring.
这点你就骗我！你没骗我吗？
You're wearing a wedding ring, Carl!You lied to me about that!
你问我有没有家庭，我曾经有 现在没有了
Didn't you lie about that?! You asked me if l had a family. l did, but l don't anymore.
是，没问题，我们马上出来
Yes? No, no, no, there is no problem. We're coming out right now.
这招真高明
Whoa, that was good. That was good.
你请饭店小弟打电话给你吗？
What, did you... you pay some hotel desk clerk to make that call for you, is that what you did?
那是卢探长，我只有一分钟
lt was Captain Luc. l've got one minute to bring you out. Captain Luc? Captain Luc!
卢探长？卢探长！
Ooh, Captain Luc. Well, Carl,
听起来真有这么一回事 我说过…
l gotta say that-that sounds pretty official to me but like l said, l... l think it's just
我认为只有你跟我 你只好亲自抓我
me and you here, it's me and you. So you're going to have to catch me.
你要相信我
Frank. Frank! You have to trust me on this!
你让他们出糗，他们很气
These people have been embarrassed, Frank. They're angry.
你偷了他们的钱还住在这儿
You rob their banks, you steal their money you live in their country.
我跟你说过了 你一定会有这下场
l told you this was what was going to happen that there was no other way for it to end.
别再犯错了
Don't make a mistake!
你演得真好
That's good. That's good, Carl, you know?
继续掰下去呀
Keep pushing that lie. Keep pushing it.
谎言掰到最后就成真了 他们会杀了你
Keep pushing till you make it true. They're going to kill you!
你走出去他们就会开枪
You walk out that door, they're going to kill you.
这是实话吗？
ls that the truth?
是
Yeah.
你有小孩吗？
You have any children, Carl?
我有一个四岁大女儿
l have a four-year-old daughter.
你敢以你女儿发誓？
You swear on your daughter?
你敢发誓？
You swear?
你发誓？
# Redit ce chant melodieux #
# Gloria #
# ln excelsius Deo #
# Gloria... #
你真的很厉害
That was really good, Carl.
我铐住他了
l have him in custody.
我逮到他了！没事了
l got him. l got him! lt's all right!
我逮到他了
lt's all right! l got him!
我要正式登录
Hey, l want it... l want it on the record.
法兰克自愿就逮，懂吗？
Frank Abagnale surrendered of his own accord. Understood? Understood?
你们带他到哪儿？我也要去
Where are you taking him? l'm... l'm supposed to go. Where are you taking him?
让我上车！
Let me in the... Let me in the car!
Hey! Let me in the car!
让我上车！
# Gloria... #
放心，我会把你引渡回美国
Don't worry, Frank! l'll have you extradited back to the United States. Don't worry.
# Gloria #
# ln excelsius Deo. #
卡尔
Carl...
Carl,
降落后记得让我打给我爸
you have to remember to let me call my father when we land.
我想趁他看到新闻前告诉他
l just want to, l want to talk to him before he sees me on television or something like that.
你看
Carl, look.
拉瓜地亚机场
That's LaGuardia right there.
44跑道
Runway 4-4.
法兰克，你爸死了
Frank, your father is dead.
很遗憾
l'm sorry.
我想等快到家再告诉你
l didn't want to say anything till we got closer to home.
他在中央车站赶火车跌下阶梯
He-He... He fell down some steps at Grand Central Station trying to catch a train.
我并不想告诉你
l didn't want to be the one to tell you.
你在说谎，对吧？
You're lying, right?
你说我能跟他说话
You said l could talk to him.
你怎么能这么做？
Carl, who are you to... who are you to say something like that, huh? Who are you to say something like that?
你说我能跟他说话 他摔断了…
You said l could talk to him. He fell, and he... and he broke his neck.
脖子，很遗憾
l'm sorry.
真的很遗憾
l'm really sorry.
该死！
Goddamn it!
我要吐了
Carl, l'm going to be sick!
不要紧，没问题
-lt's all right. lt's all right. lt's okay.
我快要吐了！ 好，咱们去厕所
Carl, l got to go to the bathroom. l'm going to be sick. Sure. Let's go in the bathroom.
可恶！
Goddamn it!
爸
Oh, Daddy...
请回座位，我们就快降落了 请你们回去
You'll have take your seat, sir. l've told you twice. We're landing. -Sorry. Thank you... -All of you.
法兰克！快出来
Frank! Come on now.
六分钟后降落，请回座位
-Frank? -We're landing in six minutes. All of you need to be in your seats
快开门！ 系紧安全带
-with your seat belts fastened. -Frank, open the door! Frank!
你来
-You do it. -Yeah.
法兰克
Frank! Frank!
请各位坐好
HANRATTY: All right, remain seated, everyone, please. FBl. Stay seated. FBl. Stay seated.
请坐好
-Please remain seated! -Stay seated. STEWARDESS: You must stay seated
老天爷
until the aircraft has come to a complete stop. HANRATTY: God almighty.
# Chestnuts roasting on an open fire... #
# Jack Frost nipping at your nose #
# Yuletide carols being sung by a choir #
# And folks dressed up like Eskimos #
# Everybody knows #
# A turkey and some mistletoe #
# Help to make the season bright #
# Tiny tots with their eyes all aglow #
# Will find it hard to sleep tonight... #
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
# They know that Santa's on his way... #
你妈咪呢？
Where's your mommy?
# ...He's loaded lots of toys and goodies on his sleigh #
# And every mother's child is gonna spy #
# To see if reindeer really know how to fly... #
# And so l'm offering this simple phrase... #
我们到了
# To kids from one to 92 #
等等！
# Although it's been said many times # # Many ways: ''Merry Christmas...'' #
把手放在头上！
Hands behind your head! # ...To you. #
让我上车，让我上车
Carl, get me in the car, please. Get me in the car.
让他上车
HANRATTY: Put him in.
你犯下的罪行非常重大…
JUDGE: Taking into account the gravity of these crimes
你的所做所为十分胆大妄为…
your history of bold and elusive behavior
你也毫不尊重美国法律…
and your complete lack of respect for the laws of the United States
我不能让你以未成年少年受审
l have no choice but to ignore your request to be treated as a minor
我判你在最高严防监狱 服刑十二年
and sentence you to 1 2 years in Atlanta's maximum security prison
并强烈建议你在服刑期间…
and recommend strongly that you be kept in isolation
一直关在禁闭室
for the entirety of that sentence.
# ...''Merry Christmas to you.'' #
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, Frank.
我带了漫画给你看
Hey, l got you some comic books here.
你女儿好吗？她叫什么？
How's your daughter? What was her name?
葛莉丝
Grace. Well... l don't know.
她跟妈妈住在芝加哥 我们不常见面
She lives with her mother in Chicago and l don't get to see her much.
公事包里有什么？
What's in the briefcase? Oh. l'm on my way to the airport.
我要赶去机场
lt's a paperhanger
有一个人在明尼苏达州犯案
who's working his way through Minnesota.
他快把我们逼疯了
Aw, geez, he's... he's driving us crazy.
你有他伪造的支票吗？
You got any of the checks?
有，五大湖储贷银行…
Yeah, yeah, l got a... a counterfeit that he drew
的假支票
on the Great Lakes Savings and Loan.
他用镂空板印刷机和打字机
See, he's just using a stencil machine and an Underwood.
一定是银行行员
Yeah, it's a teller at the bank.
什么？
Say again?
他一定是银行行员
l-lt's definitely a teller, Carl.
银行都用印章印日期
l mean, banks, they always use hand-stamps for the dates, see.
印章用久了就会磨损
They get used over and over again so they always get worn out
上面的号码会破裂
and the numbers are always cracking.
尤其是6跟9  首先破损
The sixes and the nines... see, they go first.
谢了
Thanks.
请你看一样东西
MAN: l'd like you to take a look at something for me.
你觉得怎样？
Tell me what you think.
这是假的
That's a fake. How do you know?
你怎么知道？ 边缘没有打孔
You haven't looked at it. Well, there's no perforated edge, right?
这张支票不是用机器切的
l mean, this... this check was hand-cut, not fed.
这是进口纸，太重了
Yeah... Paper is double-bonded much too heavy to be a bank check.
墨水凸出来，不是平的
Magnetic ink, it's, uh, raised against my fingers instead of flat.
闻起来也不像磁墨 应该是制图用墨水
And this doesn't smell like MlCR. lt's some kind of a... you know, some kind of a drafting ink.
文具店就买得到
You know, the kind you get at a stationery store.
法兰克
Frank...
你想替FBI财务犯罪组工作吗？
would you be interested in working with the FBl's Financial Crimes Unit?
我有工作，我负责送信
l already got a job here. You know, l, uh, deliver the mail.
我们有权力让你出狱
Frank, we have the power to take you out of prison.
你会受到FBI监护
You'd be placed in the custody of the FBl where you'd serve out the remainder of your sentence
以联邦政府员工身份服刑
as an employee of the federal government.
受到谁的监护？
Under whose custody?
我是法兰克，今天开始上班
Hi. l-l'm Frank Abagnale. l'm supposed to start work here today.
那是维京群岛的旅行社
lt's a tour company operating out of the BVl.
长官，艾先生来了
Sir, Mr. Abagnale is here.
我待会打给你
l'm going to call you back.
你好，卡尔 欢迎加入FBl
Hello, Carl. Welcome to the FBl.
我带你到你的办公室
l'll show you where you're working.
我要在这儿做多久？
Carl... how long do l have to work here? lt's 8:15 in the morning to 5:00 in the afternoon.
从早上8点到下午5点 午休45分钟
45 minutes for lunch. No, l...
我是说多长时间
l mean, how long?
每天
Every day.
直到你服满刑期
Every day, Frank, till we let you go.
票据诈欺
卡尔
-Hey, Carl. -Hi.
你好吗？
How you doing?
我没空，我正在清办公桌
lt's not a good time, Frank. l'm clearing my desk for the weekend.
我明天能跟你工作吗？
Carl, you mind if l come to work with you tomorrow?
明天是星期六
Tomorrow is Saturday.
我要去芝加哥看女儿 星期一回来
l'm flying to Chicago to see my daughter. l'll be back to work on Monday.
你要去看葛莉丝？ 我是这么打算
You're going to see Grace, huh? Well, that's the plan.
那我要做什么？
So what should l do till Monday?
抱歉，我帮不上忙
l'm sorry, kid, l can't help you there. Excuse me.
我是韩瑞提
This is Hanratty.
把他接过来
Oh, yeah, put him on.
苏先生
Mr. Sawyer.
你好
How are you?
我有那家旅行社开的芭乐票
l have a half a dozen more checks on that tour operator at the BVl.
你是怎么办到的？
How'd you do it, Frank?
你是怎么考到律师执照？
How'd you pass the bar in Louisiana?
你在这儿干嘛？
What are you doing here?
很抱歉替你惹这么多麻烦
l'm sorry l put you through all this.
你逃到欧洲会死在牢里
You go back to Europe, you're gonna die in Perpignan Prison.
你在美国逃亡会坐五十年牢
You try to run here in the States we'll send you back to Atlanta for 50 years.
我知道
l know that.
我花了四年才把你放出来
l spent four years trying to arrange your release.
我得说服我上司 和司法部长你不会逃跑
Had to convince my bosses at the FBl and the Attorney General of the United States you wouldn't run.
你为什么要帮我？
Why'd you do it?
你只是个孩子 我不是你的孩子
You're just a kid. l'm not your kid.
你说你要去芝加哥
You said you were going to Chicago.
我女儿去滑雪，不能见我
My daughter can't see me this weekend. She's going skiing.
你说她才四岁，你骗我
You said she was four years old. You're lying.
当年她才四岁，她现在十五岁
She was four when l left. Now she's 15.
我前妻再婚有十一年了
My wife's been remarried for 1 1 years.
我偶尔才见到葛莉丝
l see Grace every now and again. l don't understand.
我不明白 你当然明白
Sure you do.
有时候活在谎言里比较容易
Sometimes it's easier living the lie.
我今晚就让你走
l'm going to let you fly tonight, Frank.
我不阻止你，我知道你会回来
l'm not even going to try to stop you. That's 'cause l know you'll be back on Monday.
你怎么知道？
Yeah? How do you know l'll come back?
你看
Look. Frank...
没有人在追你
nobody's chasing you.
他还没打来吗？
Alice, has he still not called?
还没有
No, he hasn't.
早安
HANRATTY: Good morning.
今天要讨论新的支票伪造方法
l've, uh, called this meeting to discuss a new type of check fraud and counterfeiting
嫌犯窜改支票上的资料 然后到处兑现
which the unsub is washing and altering checks then passing them throughout Arizona.
这家伙很贪心 他伪造的支票有五位数字
This unsub is a big dog passing checks as large as five figures.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry l'm late.
不好意思
Sorry.
芮探员桌上有伪造支票
We have a recovered check on Agent Reiter's desk.
我们一起去看看
Why don't we step out to the bullpen?
每一行都有笔迹
There's impressions on every line.
原来的金额只有六十元
Looks like the original amount was for $60.
我能看看吗？
Mind if l take a look?
一星期前才兑现的
Cashed in Flagstaff a week ago.
他害银行损失1万6千
Cost the bank $16,000.
这是真的支票 是的
lt's a real check. Yeah.
墨水被洗掉，只要签名是真的
Yeah. lt's been washed. The only thing original is the signature.
他洗得很彻底
But it's perfect, Carl. l mean...
不是盐酸或漂白剂
l mean, this isn't hydrochloride or bleach. No.
这是新的玩意
Something new.
也许是指甲油去除剂的丙酮
Maybe a nail polish remover where the acetone removes the ink that's not been printed?
你是怎么办到的？
How did you do it, Frank?
你怎么作弊考到律师执照？
How did you cheat on the bar exam in Louisiana?
我没有作弊
l didn't cheat.
我K了两礼拜书考到执照
l studied for two weeks and l passed.
这是真的吗？
ls that the truth, Frank?
这家伙在信箱偷支票
ls that the truth? l'll bet this guy steals checks out of mailboxes.
洗掉名字写上自己的名字
He washes off their names and he puts on his own.
他是当地人？
You're saying that he's a local?
换作是我会先打电话 给银行查分额…
Well, if it were me, you know l'd call the bank first, l'd check out the balance...
确定户头里的钱够多
Make sure there's enough money in there to make it worth your while.
没错
Exactly. You know, Carl, l think this guy's pretty smart.
这家伙很聪明
l guess all we have to do now is catch him.
现在只要逮到他
We'll start first thing in the morning. We'll run the name Eric Anthony Feeders. ln Nevada, Arizona, California.
法兰克艾巴奈尔结婚26年 育有三子在中西部过平静生活
Frank Abagnale, Jr. has been married for 26 years. He has three sons and lives a quiet life in the midwest.
他于1974年出狱后 协助联邦调查局逮捕 世上最高明的支票伪造犯 并被公认是全世界最有权威的 银行诈欺专家
Since his release from prison in 197 4, Frank has helped the FBl capture some of the world's most elusive check forgers and counterfeiters, and is considered one of the world's foremost authorities on bank fraud and forgery.
他也设计多种加密支票 银行和大企业每天都在使用
Frank has also designed many of the secure checks that banks and Fortune 500 companies use every day.
为了换取他的服务 这些公司每年付他 数百万元
For his services, these companies pay Frank Abagnale, Jr. millions of dollars a year.
他们至今仍是好朋友
Frank and Carl remain close friends to this day.